{
    "Problem 6.1.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be the collection of 2\\(\\times\\)2 real matrices with nonzero determinant. Define the product of two elements in \\(G\\) as the usual matrix product. group,\\(\\wp\\)center_\n\n1. _Show that_ \\(G\\) _is a group._\n2. _Find the_ center\\__\\(Z\\) \\_of_ \\(G\\)_; that is, the set of all elements_ \\(z\\) _of_ \\(G\\) _such that_ \\(az=za\\) _for all_ \\(a\\in G\\)_._\n3. _Show that the set_ \\(O\\) _of real orthogonal matrices is a subgroup of_ \\(G\\) _(a matrix is_ orthogonal _if_ \\(AA^{t}=I\\)_, where_ \\(A^{t}\\) _denotes the transpose of A). Show by example that_ \\(O\\) _is not a normal subgroup._\n4. _Find a nontrivial homomorphism from_ \\(G\\) _onto an abelian group._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.2": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be the set of 3\\(\\times\\)3 real matrices with zeros below the diagonal and ones on the diagonal._\n\n1. _Prove_ \\(G\\) _is a group under matrix multiplication._\n2. _Determine the center of_ \\(G\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.3": {
        "Problem": "_For each of the following either give an example or else prove that no such example is possible._\n\n1. _A nonabelian group.\\_2. \\_A finite abelian group that is not cyclic._\n2. _An infinite group with a subgroup of index_ \\(5\\)_._\n3. _Two finite groups that have the same order but are not isomorphic._\n4. _A group_ \\(G\\) _with a subgroup_ \\(H\\) _that is_ not _normal._\n5. _A nonabelian group with no normal subgroups except the whole group and the unit element._\n6. _A group_ \\(G\\) _with a normal subgroup_ \\(H\\) _such that the factor group_ \\(G/H\\) _is_ not _isomorphic to any subgroup of_ \\(G\\)_._\n7. _A group_ \\(G\\) _with a subgroup_ \\(H\\) _which has index_ \\(2\\) _but is_ not _normal._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a ring with multiplicative identity \\(1\\). Call \\(x\\in R\\) a unit if \\(xy=1\\) for some \\(y\\in R\\). Let \\(G(R)\\) denote the set of units._\n\n1. _Prove_ \\(G(R)\\) _is a multiplicative group._\n2. _Let_ \\(R\\) _be the ring of complex numbers_ \\(a+bi\\)_, where_ \\(a\\) _and_ \\(b\\) _are integers. Prove_ \\(G(R)\\) _is isomorphic to_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\) _(the additive group of integers modulo* \\(4\\)*).\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.5": {
        "Problem": "_In the triangular network in \\(\\mathbb{R}^{2}\\) which is depicted below, the points \\(P_{0}\\), \\(P*{1}\\), \\(P*{2}\\), and \\(P*{3}\\) are respectively \\((0,0)\\), \\((1,0)\\), \\((0,1)\\), and \\((1,1)\\). Describe the structure of the group of all Euclidean transformations of \\(\\mathbb{R}^{2}\\) which leave this network invariant.*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.6": {
        "Problem": "_Does the set \\(G=\\{a\\in\\mathbb{R}\\mid a>0,a\\neq 1\\}\\) form a group with the operation \\(a\\*b=a^{\\log b}\\)?_",
        "Solution": "If \\(a,b\\in G\\), then \\(a>0\\) and \\(b\\neq 1\\), so \\(a^{\\log b}\\in G\\). Therefore, the operation \\(\\*\\) is well defined.\n\n_Identity._ The constant \\(e\\) is the identity since \\(a*e=a^{\\log e}=a^{1}=a\\) and \\(e*a=e^{\\log a}=a\\).\n\n_Associativity._ We have\n\n\\[(a*b)*c=c^{\\log(e^{\\log a\\log b})}=e^{\\log a\\log b\\log c}=a^{\\log(e^{\\log b \\log c})}=a*(b*c).\\]\n\n_Invertibility._ Since \\(a\\neq 1\\), \\(e^{1/\\log a}\\) exists and is an element of \\(G\\). A calculation shows that \\(a*e^{1/\\log a}=e^{1/\\log a}*a=e\\).\n\n_Solution 2._ The map \\(\\log:G\\rightarrow\\mathbb{R}\\setminus\\{0\\}\\) is a bijection that transforms the operation \\(*\\) into multiplication; that is, \\(\\log(a*b)=(\\log a)(\\log b)\\). Since \\(\\mathbb{R}\\setminus\\{0\\}\\) forms a group with respect to multiplication, \\(G\\) is a group with respect to \\(\\*\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.1.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a finite group. A conjugacy class is a set of the form_\n\n\\[C(a)=\\{bab^{-1}\\mid b\\in G\\}\\]\n\n_for some \\(a\\in G\\)._\n\n1. _Prove that the number of elements in a conjugacy class divides the order of_ \\(G\\)_._\n2. _Do all conjugacy classes have the same number of elements?_\n3. _If_ \\(G\\) _has only two conjugacy classes, prove_ \\(G\\) _has order_ \\(2\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a finite nontrivial group with the property that for any two elements \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) in \\(G\\) different from the identity, there is an element \\(c\\) in \\(G\\) such that \\(b=c^{-1}ac\\). Prove that \\(G\\) has order \\(2\\)._",
        "Solution": "Fix an element \\(a\\in G\\) different from the identity, and consider the map \\(\\varphi:G\\setminus\\{e\\}\\to G\\setminus\\{e\\}\\) defined by \\(\\varphi(c)=c^{-1}ac\\). The map is onto, so, since \\(G\\) is finite, it is one-to-one. As \\(\\varphi(a)=a\\) and \\(a^{-2}aa^{2}=a\\), it must be that \\(a^{2}=e\\). Thus, all elements of \\(G\\), other than the identity, have order \\(2\\). Then, if \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) are in \\(G\\), we have\n\n\\[ab=a(ab)^{2}b=a^{2}(ba)b^{2}=ba\\]in other words, \\(G\\) is commutative, and it follows that \\(G\\) has order 2.\n\n_Solution 2_. Since \\(G\\) is finite, it has an element of prime order \\(p\\). Hence, every element of \\(G\\), other than the identity, has order \\(p\\). Since \\(G\\) is a \\(p\\)-group, it has a nontrivial central element. Therefore, all elements are central; in other words, \\(G\\) is abelian. Hence, \\(G\\) has order 2.\n\n_Solution 3_. By our hypothesis, any two nonidentity elements are conjugate. Hence, there are two conjugacy classes: The class containing the identity and the class containing all the other elements of \\(G\\). Letting \\(n\\) be the order of \\(G\\), we see that the second conjugacy class must contain \\(n-1\\) elements. But, by the class equation, we know that the order of any conjugacy class divides the order of the group, so \\((n-1)|n\\). Solving for \\(n>0\\), we see that the only possible solution is \\(n=2\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.1.9": {
        "Problem": "_For a \\(p\\)-group of order \\(p^{4}\\), assume the center of \\(G\\) has order \\(p^{2}\\). Determine the number of conjugacy classes of \\(G\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.10": {
        "Problem": "_In a commutative group \\(G\\), let the element \\(a\\) have order \\(r\\), let \\(b\\) have order \\(s\\)\\((r,s<\\infty)\\), and assume that the greatest common divisor of \\(r\\) and \\(s\\) is \\(1\\). Show that \\(ab\\) has order \\(rs\\)._",
        "Solution": "Consider the group \\(G^{\\prime}=\\{a^{n}b^{m}\\,|\\,0\\leq n\\leq r-1,\\,0\\leq m\\leq s-1\\}\\). As the order of any element of \\(G^{\\prime}\\) divides the order of \\(G^{\\prime}\\), we have \\(|G^{\\prime}|=rs\\). This shows that \\((ab)^{k}\\) is never the identity for \\(0<k<rs\\). Clearly we have \\((ab)^{rs}=a^{r}b^{s}=e\\), so the order of \\(ab\\) is \\(rs\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.1.11": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group. For any subset \\(X\\) of \\(G\\), define its centralizer \\(C(X)\\) to be \\(\\{y\\in G\\mid xy=yx,\\forall x\\in X\\}\\). Prove the following:_\n\n1. _If_ \\(X\\subset Y\\)_, then_ \\(C(Y)\\subset C(X)\\)_._\n2. \\(X\\subset C\\left(C(X)\\right)\\)_._\n3. \\(C(X)=C\\left(C\\left(C(X)\\right)\\right)\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.1.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(D\\) be a group of order \\(2n\\), where \\(n\\) is odd, with a subgroup \\(H\\) of order \\(n\\) satisfying \\(xhx^{-1}=h^{-1}\\) for all \\(h\\) in \\(H\\) and all \\(x\\) in \\(D\\setminus H\\). Prove that \\(H\\) is commutative and that every element of \\(D\\setminus H\\) is of order \\(2\\)._\n\n### Homomorphisms and Subgroups",
        "Solution": "Let \\(g,h\\in H\\) and let \\(x\\in D\\setminus H\\). Then\n\n\\[h^{-1}g^{-1}=xhx^{-1}xgx^{-1}=xhgx^{-1}=(hg)^{-1}=g^{-1}h^{-1}\\]\n\nand we can conclude immediately from this that \\(H\\) is abelian.\n\nLet \\(x\\in D\\setminus H\\). We have [D:H]=2, so \\(x^{2}\\in H\\). By hypothesis, \\(xx^{2}x^{-1}=x^{-2}\\) or \\(x^{4}=1\\). Therefore, \\(x\\) has order 1, 2, or 4. But \\(n\\) is odd, so 4 does not divide the order of \\(D\\), so, by Lagrange's Theorem [1, pag. 41], \\(x\\) cannot have order 4. By our choice of \\(x\\), \\(x\\neq 1\\), so \\(x\\) cannot have order 1. Hence, \\(x\\) has order 2.\n\n### 6.2 Homomorphisms and Subgroups"
    },
    "Problem 6.2.1": {
        "Problem": "_How many homomorphisms are there from the group \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\) to the symmetric group on three letters?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.2": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{C}\\)\\({}^{*}\\) be the multiplicative group of nonzero complex numbers. Suppose that \\(H\\) is a subgroup of finite index of \\(\\mathbb{C}\\)\\({}^{*}\\). Prove that \\(H=\\mathbb{C}\\)\\({}^{\\*}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(n=[\\mathbb{C}^{*}:H]\\). By Lagrange's Theorem [1, page. 41], the order of any element of \\(\\mathbb{C}^{_}/H\\) divides \\(n\\). So \\(x^{n}\\in H\\) for all \\(x\\in\\mathbb{C}^{_}\\). Therefore, \\(\\left(\\mathbb{C}^{\\*}\\right)^{n}=\\mathbb{C}\\subset H\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.2.3": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a finite group and \\(H\\subset G\\) a subgroup.\\_1. \\_Show that the number of subgroups of_ \\(G\\) _of the form_ \\(xHx^{-1}\\) _for some_ \\(x\\in G\\) _is_ \\(\\leq\\) _the index of_ \\(H\\) _in_ \\(G\\)_._ 2. _Prove that some element of_ \\(G\\) _is not in any subgroup of the form_ \\(xHx^{-1}\\)_,_ \\(x\\in G\\)_._",
        "Solution": "1. The number of conjugates of \\(H\\) in \\(G\\) is \\(|G:N(H;G)|\\) where \\(N(H;G)=\\{g\\in G\\,|\\,g^{-1}Hg=H\\}\\) is the normalizer of \\(H\\). As \\(H\\subset N(H;G)\\), we have \\(|G:H|\\geq|G:N(H;G)|\\).\n\n2. By Problem 6.4.16, there is a normal subgroup of \\(G\\), \\(N\\), contained in \\(H\\), such that \\(G/N\\) is finite. By Part 1 we can find a coset \\(Ng\\in G/N\\) such that \\(Ng\\) is not contained in any conjugate \\(y^{-1}Hy/N\\) of \\(H/N\\) in \\(G/N\\). Then \\(g\\not\\in y^{-1}Hy\\) for any \\(y\\in G\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.2.4": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that the group of automorphisms of a cyclic group of prime order \\(p\\) is cyclic and find its order._",
        "Solution": "We will prove a more general result. Let \\(G=\\langle g\\rangle\\), \\(|G|=n\\), and \\(\\alpha\\in\\operatorname{Aut}G\\). As \\(\\alpha(g)\\) also generates \\(G\\), we have \\(\\alpha(g)=g^{k}\\) for some \\(1\\leq k<n\\), \\((k,n)=1\\). Conversely, \\(x\\mapsto x^{k}\\) is an automorphism of \\(G\\) for \\((k,1)=1\\). Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\) be the multiplicative group of residue classes modulo \\(n\\) relatively prime to \\(n\\). If \\(\\overline{k}\\) denotes the residue class containing \\(k\\), we can define \\(\\Phi:\\operatorname{Aut}G\\to\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\) by\n\n\\[\\Phi(\\alpha)=\\overline{k}\\qquad\\text{iff}\\qquad\\alpha(g)=g^{k}.\\]\n\nIt is clear that \\(\\Phi\\) is an isomorphism. As \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{n}\\) is an abelian group of order \\(\\varphi(n)\\) (\\(\\varphi\\) is Euler's totient function [10, pag. 77], [11, pag. 43]), so is \\(\\operatorname{Aut}G\\). When \\(n\\) is prime, these groups are also cyclic."
    },
    "Problem 6.2.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a finite group, and let \\(\\varphi\\) be an automorphism of \\(G\\) which leaves fixed only the identity element of \\(G\\)._\n\n1. _Show that every element of_ \\(G\\) _may be written in the form_ \\(g^{-1}\\varphi(g)\\)_._\n2. _If_ \\(\\varphi\\) _has order_ \\(2\\) _(i.e.,_ \\(\\varphi\\cdot\\varphi=\\mathrm{id}\\)_) show that_ \\(\\varphi\\) _is given by the formula_ \\(g\\mapsto g^{-1}\\) _and that_ \\(G\\) _is an abelian group whose order is odd._",
        "Solution": "1. If \\(g^{-1}\\varphi(g)=h^{-1}\\varphi(h)\\) for some \\(g,h\\in G\\), then \\(\\varphi(g)\\varphi(h)^{-1}=gh^{-1}\\), so, by hypothesis, \\(gh^{-1}=1\\) and \\(g=h\\). Thus, there are \\(|G|\\) elements of that form, so they must constitute all of \\(G\\).\n\n2. Using Part 1, we have, for \\(z=g^{-1}\\varphi(g)\\in G\\),\n\n\\[\\varphi(z)=\\varphi(g^{-1})\\varphi^{2}(g)=\\varphi(g^{-1})g=z^{-1}\\]\n\nso \\(g\\mapsto g^{-1}\\) is an automorphism of \\(G\\), which implies that \\(G\\) is abelian. For any \\(z\\in G\\), \\(z\\neq 1\\), we have \\(z^{-1}=\\varphi(z)\\neq z\\), so \\(G\\) has no element of order 2, and \\(|G|\\) is odd."
    },
    "Problem 6.2.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be an additive group, and \\(u,v:G\\to G\\) homomorphisms. Show that the map \\(f:G\\to G\\), \\(f(x)=x-v\\left(u(x)\\right)\\) is surjective if the map \\(h:G\\to G\\), \\(h(x)=x-u\\left(v(x)\\right)\\) is surjective._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(H\\) be the group of integers \\(\\mathrm{mod}p\\), under addition, where \\(p\\) is a prime number. Suppose that \\(n\\) is an integer satisfying \\(1\\leq n\\leq p\\), and let \\(G\\) be the group \\(H\\times H\\times\\cdots\\times H\\) (\\(n\\) factors). Show that \\(G\\) has no automorphism of order \\(p^{2}\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.9": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group and \\(H\\) a subgroup of index \\(n<\\infty\\). Prove or disprove the following statements:_\n\n1. _If_ \\(a\\in G\\)_, then_ \\(a^{n}\\in H\\)_._\n2. _If_ \\(a\\in G\\)_, then for some_ \\(k\\)_,_ \\(0<k\\leq n\\)_, we have_ \\(a^{k}\\in H\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.10": {
        "Problem": "_Find all automorphisms of the additive group of rational numbers._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(A\\) be an additively written abelian group, and \\(f,g:A\\to A\\) two group homomorphisms. Define the group homomorphisms \\(i,j:A\\to A\\) by_\n\n\\[i(a)=a-g\\left(f(a)\\right),\\ \\ \\ \\ j(a)=a-f\\left(g(a)\\right)\\ \\ \\ \\ \\ (a\\in A).\\]\n\n_Prove that the kernel of \\(i\\) is isomorphic to the kernel of \\(j\\)._",
        "Solution": "We show that \\(f\\) is an isomorphism from \\(\\ker i\\) onto \\(\\ker j\\). Let \\(y\\in\\ker i\\). We have\n\n\\[j(f(y))=f(y)-f(g(f(y)))=f(y-g(f(y)))=f(i(y))=f(0)=0.\\]\n\n[MISSING_PAGE_FAIL:339]"
    },
    "Problem 6.2.13": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group and \\(H\\) and \\(K\\) subgroups such that \\(H\\) has a finite index in \\(G\\). Prove that \\(K\\cap H\\) has a finite index in \\(K\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.14": {
        "Problem": "_Suppose the group \\(G\\) has a nontrivial subgroup \\(H\\) which is contained in every nontrivial subgroup of \\(G\\). Prove that \\(H\\) is contained in the center of \\(G\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.2.15": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group generated by \\(n\\) elements. Find an upper bound \\(N(n,k)\\) for the number of subgroups \\(H\\) of \\(G\\) with the index \\([G:H]=k\\)._\n\n### Cyclic Groups",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.3.2": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be the group \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left/\\mathbb{Z}\\right.\\) Show that for every positive integer \\(t\\), \\(G\\) has a unique cyclic subgroup of order \\(t\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.3.3": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(G\\) _be a cyclic group, and let_ \\(a,b\\in G\\) _be elements which are not squares. Prove that_ \\(ab\\) _is a square._\n2. _Give an example to show that this result is false if the group is not cyclic._",
        "Solution": "1. Let \\(G=\\langle c\\rangle\\). We have \\(a=c^{r}\\) and \\(b=c^{s}\\) for some positive odd integers \\(r\\) and \\(s\\), so \\(ab=c^{r+s}\\) with \\(r+s\\) even, and \\(ab\\) is a square.\n\n2. Let \\(G=\\mathbb{Q}\\,^{\\*}\\), the multiplicative group of the rational numbers, \\(a=2\\), and \\(b=3\\). Then \\(ab=6\\), and none of these is a square in \\(G\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.3.4": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that any group of order \\(77\\) is cyclic._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.3.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group of order \\(2p\\), where \\(p\\) is an odd prime. Assume that \\(G\\) has a normal subgroup of order \\(2\\). Prove that \\(G\\) is cyclic._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(e\\) be the identity in \\(G\\), and let \\(N=\\{e,a\\}\\) be the normal subgroup of order \\(2\\). If \\(x\\in G\\), then \\(x^{-1}ax\\in N\\) and certainly does not equal \\(e\\), so it equals \\(a\\). Thus, \\(xa=ax\\) for all \\(x\\in G\\). The quotient group \\(G/N\\) has order \\(p\\) and so is cyclic. Let \\(x\\) be any element not in \\(N\\). Then the coset of \\(x\\) in \\(G/N\\) has order \\(p\\), so, in particular, the order of \\(x\\) itself is not \\(2\\). But the order of \\(x\\) divides \\(2p\\), so it must be \\(p\\) or \\(2p\\). In the latter case, \\(G\\) is the cyclic group generated by \\(x\\). In the former case, since \\(xa=ax\\), we have \\((xa)^{p}=x^{p}a^{p}=a\\), so \\((xa)^{2p}=a^{2}=e\\), and \\(xa\\) has order \\(2p\\), which means \\(G\\) is the cyclic group generated by \\(xa\\).\n\n### 6.4 Normality, Quotients, and Homomorphisms"
    },
    "Problem 6.3.6": {
        "Problem": "_A finite abelian group \\(G\\) has the property that for each positive integer \\(n\\) the set \\(\\{x\\in G\\,|\\,x^{n}=1\\}\\) has at most \\(n\\) elements. Prove that \\(G\\) is cyclic, and deduce that every finite field has cyclic multiplicative group._\n\n### Normality, Quotients, and Homomorphisms",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.4.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(H\\) be a subgroup of a finite group \\(G\\)._\n\n1. _Show that_ \\(H\\) _has the same number of left cosets as right cosets._\n\n[MISSING_PAGE_FAIL:97]",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.4.10": {
        "Problem": "_Suppose \\(H_{i}\\) is a normal subgroup of a group \\(G\\) for \\(1\\leq i\\leq k\\), such that \\(H*{i}\\cap H*{j}=\\{1\\}\\) for \\(i\\neq j\\). Prove that \\(G\\) contains a subgroup isomorphic to \\(H*{1}\\times H*{2}\\times\\cdots\\times H*{k}\\) if \\(k=2\\), but not necessarily if \\(k\\geq 3\\).*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.4.11": {
        "Problem": "\\(G\\) _is a group of order \\(n\\), \\(H\\) a proper subgroup of order \\(m\\), and \\((n/m)!<2n\\). Prove \\(G\\) has a proper normal subgroup different from the identity._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\{a*{1}H,a*{2}H,\\ldots,a\\_{\\frac{n}{m}}H\\}\\) be the set of distinct cosets of \\(H\\). \\(G\\) acts on on this set by left multiplication and any \\(g\\in G\\) permutes these \\(n/m\\) cosets. This group action defines a map\n\n\\[\\varphi:G\\to S\\_{\\frac{n}{m}}\\]\n\nfrom \\(G\\) to the permutation group on \\(n/m\\) objects. There are two cases to consider depending on \\(\\varphi\\) being injective or not.\n\nIf \\(\\varphi\\) is not injective, then \\(\\ker\\varphi\\) is a normal subgroup \\(K\\neq\\{e\\}\\); and \\(K\\neq G\\), as well, because if \\(g\\not\\in H\\), \\(gH\\neq H\\); so \\(g\\) is not a trivial permutation.\n\nIf \\(\\varphi\\) is injective, then \\(|\\varphi(G)|=n\\), and \\(\\varphi(G)\\) is a subgroup of \\(S*{\\frac{n}{m}}\\). But \\([S*{\\frac{n}{m}}:\\varphi(G)]=|S*{\\frac{n}{m}}|/|\\varphi(G)|=(\\frac{n}{m})!/n<2\\). So \\(|S*{\\frac{n}{m}}:\\varphi(G)|=1\\), that is, \\(G\\) is isomorphic to \\(S*{\\frac{n}{m}}\\), and in that case, \\(A*{\\frac{n}{m}}\\) is a nontrivial normal subgroup."
    },
    "Problem 6.4.13": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group whose order is twice an odd number. For \\(g\\) in \\(G\\), let \\(\\lambda_{g}\\) denote the permutation of \\(G\\) given by \\(\\lambda*{g}(x)=gx\\) for \\(x\\in G\\).*\n\n1. _Let_ \\(g\\) _be in_ \\(G\\)_. Prove that the permutation_ \\(\\lambda*{g}\\) \\_is even if and only if the order of* \\(g\\) _is odd._\n2. _Let_ \\(N=\\{g\\in G\\mid\\operatorname{order}(g)\\text{ is odd}\\}\\)_. Prove that_ \\(N\\) _is a normal subgroup of_ \\(G\\) _of index_ \\(2\\)_._",
        "Solution": "1. The cycles of \\(\\lambda\\_{g}\\) are the right cosets \\(\\langle g\\rangle x\\) of the subgroup \\(\\langle g\\rangle\\) in \\(G\\), so the lengths of each one is the order of \\(g\\), and the number of cycles is \\([G:\\langle g\\rangle]\\).\n\nIf the order of \\(g\\) is odd, then each cycle has odd length, so each cycle is even, and so is \\(\\lambda\\_{g}\\).\n\nIf the order of \\(g\\) is even, then each cycle is of even length and, therefore, odd. Also,\n\n\\[[G:\\langle g\\rangle]\\cdot|\\langle g\\rangle|=|G|\\]\n\nis odd. As \\([G:\\langle g\\rangle]\\) is the number of cycles, \\(\\lambda\\_{g}\\) is odd.\n\n2. Let \\(\\varphi:G\\rightarrow\\{-1,1\\}\\) be defined by \\(g\\mapsto\\varphi(g)=\\) sign of \\(\\lambda\\_{g}\\). \\(\\varphi\\) is a morphism and, by Part 1, its kernel is \\(N\\). So \\(N\\) is a normal subgroup of \\(G\\) with index 1 or 2. By Cauchy's Theorem [1, pag. 61], \\(G\\) has an element of order 2, which is not in \\(N\\), so \\(N\\) has order 2."
    },
    "Problem 6.4.14": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group, \\(G^{\\prime}\\) its commutator subgroup, and \\(N\\) a normal subgroup of \\(G\\). Suppose that \\(N\\) is cyclic. Prove that \\(gn=ng\\) for all \\(g\\in G^{\\prime}\\) and all \\(n\\in N\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(g=xyx^{-1}y^{-1}\\) be a commutator. It suffices to show that conjugation by \\(g\\) fixes every element of \\(N\\). As \\(N\\) is cyclic, Aut(N) is abelian, and, because \\(N\\) is normal, conjugation by any element of \\(G\\) is an automorphism of \\(N\\). Let \\(\\varphi*{x}\\) be the automorphism of conjugation by \\(x\\). We have \\(\\varphi*{x}\\varphi*{y}=\\varphi*{y}\\varphi*{x}\\). Hence, for \\(n\\in N\\), \\(gng^{-1}=\\varphi*{x}\\circ\\varphi*{y}\\circ\\varphi*{x}^{-1}\\circ\\varphi\\_{y}^{-1 }(n)=n\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.4.15": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group and \\(N\\) be a normal subgroup of \\(G\\) with \\(N\\neq G\\). Suppose that there does not exist a subgroup \\(H\\) of \\(G\\) satisfying \\(N\\subset H\\subset G\\) and \\(N\\neq H\\neq G\\). Prove that the index of \\(N\\) in \\(G\\) is finite and equal to a prime number._",
        "Solution": "We will show that if the index of \\(N\\) in \\(G\\) is not finite and equal to a prime number, then there is a subgroup \\(H\\) properly between \\(N\\) and \\(G\\). Since any nontrivial proper subgroup of \\(G/N\\) is the image of such a subgroup, we need only look at subgroups of \\(G/N\\).\n\nSuppose first that the index of \\(N\\) in \\(G\\) is infinite, and let \\(g\\) be an element of \\(G/N\\). If \\(g\\) is a generator of \\(G/N\\), then \\(G/N\\) is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\), and the element \\(g^{2}\\) generates a proper nontrivial subgroup of \\(G/N\\). Otherwise, \\(g\\) generates such a subgroup.\n\nSuppose that the index of \\(N\\) in \\(G\\) is finite but not a prime number. Let \\(p\\) be any prime divisor of the index. By Cauchy's Theorem [19, pag. 152], there is an element of order \\(p\\) in \\(G/N\\). This element cannot generate the whole group, so it generates a nontrivial proper subgroup of \\(G/N\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.4.16": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group having a subgroup \\(A\\) of finite index. Prove that there is a normal subgroup \\(N\\) of \\(G\\) contained in \\(A\\) such that \\(N\\) is of finite index in \\(G\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let the index of \\(A\\) in \\(G\\) be \\(n\\). \\(G\\) acts by left multiplication on the cosets \\(gA\\), and this gives a homomorphism into the group of permutations of the cosets, which has order \\(n!\\). The kernel, \\(N\\), of this homomorphism is contained in \\(A\\), so the index of \\(N\\) in \\(G\\) is, at most, \\(n!\\).\n\n### 6.5 \\(S*{n}\\), \\(A*{n}\\), \\(D\\_{n}\\),..."
    },
    "Problem 6.4.17": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(H\\) be the quotient of an abelian group \\(G\\) by a subgroup \\(K\\). Prove or disprove each of the following statements:_\n\n1. _If_ \\(H\\) _is finite cyclic then_ \\(G\\) _is isomorphic to the direct product of_ \\(H\\) _and_ \\(K\\)_._\n2. _If_ \\(H\\) _is a direct product of infinite cyclic groups then_ \\(G\\) _is isomorphic to the direct product of_ \\(H\\) _and_ \\(K\\)_._\n\n### \\(S*{n}\\), \\(A*{n}\\), \\(D\\_{n}\\),...",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}_{2}=\\{0,1\\}\\) be the field with two elements. Let \\(G\\) be the group of invertible 2\\(\\times\\)2 matrices with entries in \\(\\mathbf{F}_{2}\\). Show that \\(G\\) is isomorphic to \\(S_{3}\\), the group of permutations of three objects.\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.2": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(S_{n}\\) denote the group of permutations of \\(n\\) letters. Find four different subgroups of \\(S*{4}\\) isomorphic to \\(S*{3}\\) and nine isomorphic to \\(S*{2}\\).*",
        "Solution": "Think of \\(S*{4}\\) as permuting the set \\(\\{1,2,3,4\\}\\). For \\(1\\leq i\\leq 4\\), let \\(G*{i}\\subset S*{4}\\) be the set of all permutations which fix \\(i\\). Clearly, \\(G*{i}\\) is a subgroup of \\(S*{4}\\); since the elements of \\(G*{i}\\) may freely permute the three elements of \\(\\{1,2,3,4\\}\\setminus\\{i\\}\\), it follows that \\(G*{i}\\) is isomorphic to \\(S*{3}\\). Thus, the \\(G*{i}\\)'s are the desired four subgroups isomorphic to \\(S*{3}\\).\n\nSimilarly, for \\(i,j\\in\\{1,2,3,4\\}\\), \\(i\\neq j\\), let \\(H*{ij}\\) be the set of permutations which fix \\(i\\) and \\(j\\). Again \\(H*{ij}\\) is a subgroup of \\(S*{4}\\), and since its elements can freely permute the other two elements, each must be isomorphic to \\(S*{2}\\). Since for each pair \\(i\\) and \\(j\\) we must get a distinct subgroup, this gives us six such subgroups.\n\nFinally, note that \\(S*{2}\\) is of order 2 and so is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}*{2}\\). Therefore, any subgroup of \\(S*{4}\\) which contains the identity and an element of order 2 is isomorphic to \\(S*{2}\\). Consider the following three subgroups: \\(\\{1,(1\\,2)(3\\,4)\\}\\), \\(\\{1,(1\\,3)(2\\,4)\\}\\), and \\(\\{1,(1\\,4)(2\\,3)\\}\\). None of these three groups fix any of the elements of \\(\\{1,2,3,4\\}\\), so they are not isomorphic to any of the \\(H\\_{ij}\\). Thus, we have found the final three desired subgroups."
    },
    "Problem 6.5.3": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a subgroup of \\(S_{5}\\), the group of all permutations on the set \\(\\{1,2,3,4,5\\}\\). Prove that if \\(G\\) contains a \\(5\\)-cycle and a \\(2\\)-cycle, then \\(G=S*{5}\\).*\n\n_Hint: Recall that if \\((i_{1}\\,i*{2}\\,\\cdots i*{n})\\) is a cycle and \\(\\sigma\\) is any permutation, then\\_\n\n\\[\\sigma(i*{1}\\,i*{2}\\,\\cdots i*{n})\\sigma^{-1}=\\left(\\sigma(i*{1})\\,\\sigma(i*{ 2})\\,\\cdots\\,\\sigma(i*{n})\\right).\\]",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\sigma\\) be a 5-cycle and \\(\\tau\\) a 2-cycle. By renaming the elements of the set, we may assume \\(\\sigma=(1\\ 2\\ 3\\ 4\\ 5)\\) and \\(\\tau=(a\\ b)\\). Letting \\(\\sigma\\) act repeatedly on \\(\\tau\\) as in the hint, we get the five transpositions \\((a+i\\ b+i)\\), \\(1\\leq i\\leq 5\\), where we interpret \\(a+i\\) to be \\(a+i-5\\) if \\(a+i>5\\). Fixing \\(i\\) such that \\(a+i-5=1\\) and letting \\(c=b+i\\), we see that \\(G\\) contains the five transpositions \\((1\\ c)\\), \\((2\\ c+1),\\ldots,(5\\ c+4)\\). Since \\(a\\neq b\\), \\(c\\neq 1\\).\n\nLet \\(d=c-1\\). Since \\(d\\) does not equal 0 or 5, these five transpositions can be written as \\((c+nd\\ c+(n+1)d)\\), \\(0\\leq n\\leq 4\\). By the Induction Principle [11, pag. 7] the hint shows that \\(G\\) contains the four transpositions\n\n\\[(1\\ c+nd)=(1\\ c+(n-1)d)(c+(n-1)d\\ c+nd)(1\\ c+(n-1)d),\\]\n\n\\(1\\leq n\\leq 4\\). Since they are distinct, it follows that \\(G\\) contains the four transpositions \\((1\\ 2)\\), \\((1\\ 3)\\), \\((1\\ 4)\\), and \\((1\\ 5)\\). Applying the hint a third time, we see that \\((i\\ j)=(1\\ i)(1\\ j)(1\\ i)\\) is an element of \\(G\\) for all \\(i\\) and \\(j\\), \\(1\\leq i,j\\leq 5\\). Hence, \\(G\\) contains all of the 2-cycles. Since every element in \\(S*{n}\\) can be written as the product of 2-cycles, we see that \\(G\\) is all of \\(S*{n}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.5.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a subgroup of the symmetric group on six letters, \\(\\mathrm{S}_{6}\\). Assume that \\(G\\) has an element of order \\(6\\). Prove that \\(G\\) has a normal subgroup \\(H\\) of index \\(2\\).\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(S_{7}\\) be the group of permutations of a set of seven elements. Find all \\(n\\) such that some element of \\(S*{7}\\) has order \\(n\\).*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.6": {
        "Problem": "\\(S*{9}\\) \\_is the group of permutations of the set of integers from \\(1\\) to \\(9\\).*\n\n1. _Exhibit an element of_ \\(S*{9}\\) \\_of order* \\(20\\)_._\n2. _Prove that no element of_ \\(S*{9}\\) \\_has order* \\(18\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(S_{9}\\) denote the group of permutations of \\(\\{1,2,\\ldots,9\\}\\) and let \\(A*{9}\\) be the subgroup consisting of all even permutations. Denote by \\(1\\in S*{9}\\) the identity permutation. Determine the minimum of all positive integers \\(m\\) such that every \\(\\sigma\\in S*{9}\\) satisfies \\(\\sigma^{m}=1\\). Determine also the minimum of all positive integers \\(m\\) such that every \\(\\sigma\\in A*{9}\\) satisfies \\(\\sigma^{m}=1\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "The order of a \\(k\\)-cycle is \\(k\\), so the smallest \\(m\\) which simultaneously annihilates all 9-cycles, 8-cycles, 7-cycles, and 5-cycles is \\(2^{3}\\cdot 3^{2}\\cdot 5\\cdot 7=2520\\). Any \\(n\\)-cycle, \\(n\\leq 9\\), raised to this power is annihilated, so \\(n=2520\\).\n\nTo compute \\(n\\) for \\(A*{9}\\), note that an 8-cycle is an odd permutation, so no 8-cycles are in \\(A*{9}\\). Therefore, \\(n\\) need only annihilate 4-cycles (since a 4-cycle times a transposition is in \\(A\\_{9}\\)), 9-cycles, 7-cycles, and 5-cycles. Thus, \\(n=2520/2=1260\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.5.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(S_{999}\\) denote the group of all permutations of \\(\\{1,\\ldots,999\\}\\), and let \\(G\\subset S*{999}\\) be an abelian subgroup of order \\(1111\\). Prove that there exists \\(i\\in\\{1,\\ldots,999\\}\\) such that for all \\(\\sigma\\in G\\), one has \\(\\sigma(i)=i\\).*",
        "Solution": "We have \\(1111=11\\times 101\\), the product of two primes. So \\(G\\) is cyclic, say \\(G=\\langle a\\rangle\\). From \\(1111>999\\), it follows that \\(a\\), when written as a product of disjoint cycles, has no cycles of length 1111. Therefore, all cycles of \\(a\\) have lengths 1, 11, and 101. Let there be \\(x\\), \\(y\\), and \\(z\\) cycles of lengths, respectively, \\(1\\), \\(11\\), and \\(101\\). If \\(x>0\\), then \\(a\\) has a fixed point, and this is then the desired fixed point for all of \\(G\\). So assume that \\(x=0\\). Then \\(11x+101z=999\\). It follows that \\(2z\\equiv 9\\pmod{11}\\), so \\(z\\equiv 10\\pmod{11}\\), and, therefore, \\(z\\geq 10\\). But then \\(999=11y+101z\\geq 1010\\), a contradiction."
    },
    "Problem 6.5.10": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group of permutations of a set \\(S\\) of \\(n\\) elements. Assume \\(G\\) is transitive; that is, for any \\(x\\) and \\(y\\) in \\(S\\), there is some \\(\\sigma\\in G\\) with \\(\\sigma(x)=y\\)._\n\n1. _Prove that_ \\(n\\) _divides the order of_ \\(G\\)_._\n2. _Suppose_ \\(n=4\\)_. For which integers_ \\(k\\geq 1\\) _can such a_ \\(G\\) _have order_ \\(4k\\)",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.11": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a transitive subgroup of the group \\(S_{n}\\) of permutations of the set \\(\\{1,\\ldots,n\\}.\\) Suppose that \\(G\\) is a simple group and that \\(\\sim\\) is an equivalence relation on \\(\\{1,\\ldots,n\\}\\) such that \\(i\\sim j\\) implies that \\(\\sigma(i)\\sim\\sigma(j)\\) for all \\(\\sigma\\in G\\). What can you conclude about the relationship \\(\\sim\\)?\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.5.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(D_{n}\\) be the dihedral group, the group of rigid motions of a regular n-gon \\((n\\geq 3).\\) (It is a noncommutative group of order \\(2n\\).) Determine its center \\(C=\\{c\\in D*{n}\\mid cx=xc\\ for\\ all\\ x\\in D*{n}\\}.\\)\\_",
        "Solution": "To determine the center of\n\n\\[D\\_{n}=\\langle a,b\\,|\\,a^{n}=b^{2}=1,ba=a^{-1}b\\rangle\\]\n\n(\\(a\\) is a rotation by \\(2\\pi/n\\) and \\(b\\) is a flip), it suffices to find those elements which commute with the generators \\(a\\) and \\(b\\). Since \\(n\\geq 3\\), \\(a^{-1}\\neq a\\). Therefore,\n\n\\[a^{r+1}b=a(a^{r}b)=(a^{r}b)a=a^{r-1}b\\]\n\nso \\(a^{2}=1\\), a contradiction; thus, no element of the form \\(a^{r}b\\) is in the center. Similarly, if for \\(1\\leq s<n\\), \\(a^{s}b=ba^{s}=a^{-s}b\\), then \\(a^{2s}=1\\), which is possible only if \\(2s=n\\). Hence, \\(a^{s}\\) commutes with \\(b\\) if and only if \\(n=2s\\). So, if \\(n=2s\\), the center of \\(D\\_{n}\\) is \\(\\{1,a^{s}\\}\\); if \\(n\\) is odd the center is \\(\\{1\\}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.5.13": {
        "Problem": "_How many Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroups does the dihedral group \\(D_{n}\\) of order \\(2n\\) have, when \\(n\\) is odd?\\_\n\n### 6.6 Direct Products",
        "Solution": "The number of Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroups of \\(D*{n}\\) is odd and divides \\(n\\). Each Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroup is cyclic of order \\(2\\), since \\(2^{1}\\) is the largest power of \\(2\\) dividing the order of the group. By considering the elements of \\(D*{n}\\) as symmetries of a regular \\(n\\)-gon, we see that there are \\(n\\) reflections through axes dividing the \\(n\\)-gon in half, and each of these generates a different subgroup of order \\(2\\). Thus, the answer is that there are exactly \\(n\\) Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroups in \\(D\\_{n}\\) when \\(n\\) is odd.\n\n### 6.6 Direct Products"
    },
    "Problem 6.6.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a finite group and \\(G_{1}=G\\times G\\). Suppose that \\(G*{1}\\) has exactly four normal subgroups. Show that \\(G\\) is simple and nonabelian.*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.6.2": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\), the additive group of rational numbers, cannot be written as the direct sum of two nontrivial subgroups. Note: See also Problems 6.3.1 and 6.7.2._",
        "Solution": "Suppose \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) was the direct sum of two nontrivial subgroups \\(A\\) and \\(B\\). Fix \\(a\\neq 0\\) in \\(A\\) and \\(b\\neq 0\\) in \\(B\\). We can write \\(a=a*{0}/a*{1}\\) and \\(b=b*{0}/b*{1}\\), where the \\(a*{i}\\)'s and \\(b*{i}\\)'s are nonzero integers. Since \\(A\\) and \\(B\\) are subgroups, \\(na\\in A\\) and \\(nb\\in B\\) for all integers \\(n\\). In particular,\\((a*{1}b*{0})a\\in A\\) and \\((b*{1}a*{0})b\\in B\\). But\n\n\\[(a*{1}b*{0})a=(a*{1}b*{0})a*{0}/a*{1}=a*{0}b*{0}=(b*{1}a*{0})b*{0}/b*{1}=(b*{1}a* {0})b.\\]\n\nHence, \\(A\\) and \\(B\\) have a nontrivial intersection, a contradiction."
    },
    "Problem 6.6.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G_{1}\\), \\(G*{2}\\), and \\(G*{3}\\) be finite groups, each of which is generated by its commutators (elements of the form \\(xyx^{-1}y^{-1}\\)). Let \\(A\\) be a subgroup of \\(G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\times G*{3}\\), which maps surjectively, by the natural projection map, to the partial products \\(G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\), \\(G*{1}\\times G*{3}\\) and \\(G*{2}\\times G*{3}\\). Show that \\(A\\) is equal to \\(G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\times G*{3}\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\pi*{3}:A\\to G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\) be the natural projection map. We have \\(\\ker\\pi*{3}=\\{(1,1,g*{3})\\in A\\}\\). Let \\(N*{3}=\\{g*{3}\\,|\\,(1,1,g*{3})\\in\\ker\\pi*{3}\\}\\). Since \\(\\ker\\pi*{3}\\) is a normal subgroup of \\(A\\), \\(N*{3}\\) is normal in \\(G*{3}\\). Let \\(A^{\\prime}=G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\times G*{3}/N*{3}\\). Since \\(\\pi*{3}\\) is onto, for any \\((g*{1},g*{2})\\in G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\), there exists \\(g*{3}\\in G*{3}\\) such that \\((g*{1},g*{2},g*{3})\\in A\\), and, thus, \\((g*{1},g*{2},\\overline{g\\_{3}})\\in A^{\\prime}\\).\n\nDefine the map \\(\\varphi:G*{1}\\times G*{2}\\to G*{3}/N*{3}\\) by \\(\\varphi(g*{1},g*{2})=\\overline{g*{3}}\\), where \\(g*{3}\\) is such that \\((g*{1},g*{2},g*{3})\\in A\\). This is well defined, for if \\((g*{1},g*{2},g*{3})\\) and \\((g*{1},g*{2},h*{3})\\) are both in \\(A\\), then \\((1,1,g*{3}h*{3}^{-1})\\in A\\), so \\(g*{3}h*{3}^{-1}\\in N*{3}\\), which, in turn, implies that \\(\\overline{g*{3}}=\\overline{h*{3}}\\). The map \\(\\varphi\\) is clearly a homomorphism. Furthermore, since \\(\\pi*{1}:A\\to G*{2}\\times G*{3}\\) is onto, if \\(g*{3}\\in G*{3}\\), there exist \\(g*{1}\\in G*{1}\\) and \\(g*{2}\\in G*{2}\\) such that \\((g*{1},g*{2},g*{3})\\in A\\). Thus, \\(\\varphi(g*{1},g*{2})=\\overline{g\\_{3}}\\) so \\(\\varphi\\) is onto.\n\nTherefore, \\(\\varphi(G*{1}\\times\\{1\\})\\) and \\(\\varphi(\\{1\\}\\times G*{2})\\) are subgroups of \\(G*{3}/N*{3}\\) which commute with each other. If these two subgroups were equal to one another and to \\(G*{3}/N*{3}\\), then \\(G*{3}/N*{3}\\) would be abelian. As \\(G*{3}\\) is generated by its commutator subgroup, this would imply \\(G*{3}/N*{3}\\) to be trivial or, equivalently, \\(G*{3}=N*{3}\\), which we assumed not to be the case. So we may assume that \\(\\varphi(\\{1\\}\\times G*{2})\\neq G*{3}/N*{3}\\). Pick \\(\\overline{g*{3}}\\in G*{3}/N*{3}\\setminus\\varphi(\\{1\\}\\times G*{2})\\). Since \\(\\pi*{2}:A\\to G*{1}\\times G*{3}\\) is onto, there exists a \\(g*{2}\\in G*{2}\\) such that \\((1,g*{2},g*{3})\\in A\\). Hence, \\(\\varphi(1,g*{2})=\\overline{g*{3}}\\), contradicting our choice of \\(\\overline{g*{3}}\\).\n\nTherefore, we must have that \\(N*{3}=G*{3}\\), so \\(\\{1\\}\\times\\{1\\}\\times G*{3}\\subset A\\). Similar arguments show that \\(\\{1\\}\\times G*{2}\\times\\{1\\}\\) and \\(G\\_{1}\\times\\{1\\}\\times\\{1\\}\\) are contained in \\(A\\) and, thus, \\(A=G\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.6.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(A\\) be a subgroup of an abelian group \\(B.\\) Assume that \\(A\\) is a direct summand of \\(B\\), i.e., there exists a subgroup \\(X\\) of \\(B\\) such that \\(A\\cap X=0\\) and such that \\(B=X+A.\\) Suppose that \\(C\\) is a subgroup of \\(B\\) satisfying \\(A\\subset C\\subset B.\\) Is \\(A\\) necessarily a direct summand of \\(C\\)?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.7.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{Q}_{+}\\) be the multiplicative group of positive rational numbers.\\_\n\n1. _Is_ \\(\\mathbb{Q}_{+}\\) \\_torsion free?_\n2. _Is_ \\(\\mathbb{Q}_{+}\\) \\_free?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.7.2": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that the additive group of \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\), the rational number field, is not finitely generated._\n\n_Note: See also Problems 6.3.1 and 6.6.2._",
        "Solution": "Suppose \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) is finitely generated, with generators\n\n\\[\\alpha*{1}/\\beta*{1},\\ldots,\\alpha*{k}/\\beta*{k}\\qquad\\alpha*{i},\\beta*{i}\\in \\mathbb{Z}.\\]\n\nThen any element of \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) can be written as \\(\\sum n*{i}\\alpha*{i}/\\beta*{i}\\), where the \\(n*{i}\\)'s are integers. This sum can be written as a single fraction with denominator \\(s=\\beta*{1}\\cdots\\beta*{k}\\). Consider a prime \\(p\\) which does not divide \\(s\\). Then we have \\(1/p=r/s\\) for some integer \\(r\\), or \\(pr=s\\), contradicting the fact that \\(p\\) does not divide \\(s\\). Hence, \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) cannot be finitely generated.\n\n_Solution 2._ Suppose \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) is finitely generated, then using the solution to Part 1 of Problem 6.3.1, \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) is cyclic, which is a contradiction."
    },
    "Problem 6.7.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be a group with generators \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) satisfying_\n\n\\[a^{-1}b^{2}a=b^{3},\\qquad b^{-1}a^{2}b=a^{3}.\\]\n\n_Is \\(G\\) trivial?_",
        "Solution": "We start with the given relations\n\n\\[(1)\\quad a^{-1}b^{2}a=b^{3}\\qquad\\text{and}\\qquad(2)\\quad b^{-1}a^{2}b=a^{3}.\\]\n\nFrom (1), we get \\(a^{-1}b^{4}a=b^{6}\\) and\n\n\\[a^{-2}b^{4}a^{2}=a^{-1}b^{6}a=(a^{-1}b^{2})b^{4}a=b^{3}(a^{-1}b^{4}a)=b^{3}b^{6} =b^{9}\\]\n\nusing the relation just obtained and (2), we get\n\n\\[b^{9}=(a^{-2})b^{4}a^{2}=ba^{-3}b^{-1}b^{4}(a^{2})=ba^{-3}b^{-1}b^{4}ba^{3}b^{-1 }=ba^{-3}b^{4}a^{3}b^{-1},\\]\n\nand we conclude that\n\n\\[a^{-3}b^{4}a^{3}=b^{9}=a^{-2}b^{4}a^{2}\\]\n\nfrom which we obtain \\(ab^{4}=b^{4}a.\\) This, combined with the square of relation \\((1)\\,(a^{-1}b^{4}a=b^{6}),\\) gives \\(b^{2}=1\\) and substitution back in (1) shows that \\(b=1;\\) then, substituting that into relation (2), we see that \\(a=1,\\) so the group is trivial."
    },
    "Problem 6.7.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G_{n}\\) be the free group on \\(n\\) generators. Show that \\(G*{2}\\) and \\(G*{3}\\) are not isomorphic.\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.7.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(G\\) be an abelian group which is generated by, at most, \\(n\\) elements. Show that each subgroup of \\(G\\) is again generated by, at most, \\(n\\) elements._",
        "Solution": "We use the Induction Principle [11, pag. 7]. For \\(n=1,\\) the result is obvious.\n\nSuppose \\(g*{1},\\ldots,g*{n}\\) generate the group \\(G\\) and let \\(H\\) be a subgroup of \\(G.\\) If \\(H\\subset\\langle g*{2},\\ldots,g*{n}\\rangle,\\) by the induction hypothesis, \\(H\\) is generated by \\(n-1\\) elements or fewer. Otherwise let\n\n\\[y=g*{1}^{m*{1}}\\cdots g*{n}^{m*{n}}\\in H\\]\n\nbe such that \\(|m*{1}|\\) is minimal but nonzero. We can assume, without loss of generality, that \\(m*{1}>0.\\) For any \\(z\\in H,\\)\n\n\\[z=g*{1}^{k*{1}}\\cdots g*{n}^{k*{n}}\\]there are integers \\(q\\) and \\(r\\) such that \\(k*{1}=qm*{1}+r\\) and \\(0\\leq r<m*{1}\\). Then the exponent of \\(g*{1}\\) in \\(zy^{-q}\\) is \\(r\\), and, by the choice of \\(m\\_{1}\\), we obtain \\(r=0\\). Hence,\n\n\\[H=\\langle y,K\\rangle\\quad\\text{where}\\quad K=H\\cap\\langle g*{2},\\dots,g*{n}\\rangle.\\]\n\nBy the induction hypothesis, \\(K\\) is generated by, at most, \\(n-1\\) elements, and the result follows."
    },
    "Problem 6.7.9": {
        "Problem": "_Determine all finitely generated abelian groups \\(G\\) which have only finitely many automorphisms._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.7.10": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(A\\) be a finite abelian group, and \\(m\\) the maximum of the orders of the elements of \\(A\\). Put \\(S=\\{a\\in A\\mid|a|=m\\}\\). Prove that \\(A\\) is generated by \\(S\\)._\n\n### 6.8 Finite Groups",
        "Solution": "By the Structure Theorem for finite abelian groups [11, pag. 109], there are integers \\(m*{1},\\dots,m*{k}\\), \\(m*{j}|m*{j+1}\\) for \\(1\\leq j\\leq k-1\\), such that \\(A\\) is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{m_{1}}\\oplus\\dots\\oplus\\mathbb{Z}_{m_{k}}\\). We identify \\(A\\) with this direct sum. Clearly \\(m=m\\_{k}\\). Therefore, \\(S\\) must contain the elements of the form \\((0,0,\\dots,1)\\) and \\((0,\\dots,0,1,0,\\dots,1)\\), where the middle \\(1\\) is in the \\(j^{th}\\) position, \\(1\\leq j\\leq k-1\\). Hence, using elements in \\(S\\), we can generate all the elements of \\(A\\) which are zero everywhere except in the \\(j^{th}\\) position. These, in turn, clearly generate \\(A\\), so \\(S\\) generates \\(A\\) as well.\n\n### 6.8 Finite Groups"
    },
    "Problem 6.8.1": {
        "Problem": "_List, to within isomorphism, all the finite groups whose orders do not exceed \\(5\\). Explain why your list is complete and why no two groups on the list are isomorphic._",
        "Solution": "Any group with one element must be the trivial group.\n\nBy Lagrange's Theorem [11, pag. 41], any group with prime order is cyclic and so abelian. Therefore, by the Structure Theorem for abelian groups [11, pag. 109], every group of orders \\(2\\), \\(3\\), or \\(5\\) is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\), \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{3}\\), or \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{5}\\), respectively.\n\nIf a group \\(G\\) has order \\(4\\), it is either cyclic, and so abelian, or each of its elements has order \\(2\\). In this case, we must have \\(1=(ab)^{2}=abab\\) or \\(ba=ab\\), so the group is abelian. Then, again by the Structure Theorem for abelian groups, a group of order \\(4\\) must be isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\) or \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\oplus\\mathbb{Z}\\_{2}\\). These two groups of order \\(4\\) are not isomorphic since only one of them has an element of order \\(4\\).\n\nSince groups of different orders can not be isomorphic, it follows that all of the groups on this list are distinct."
    },
    "Problem 6.8.2": {
        "Problem": "_Show that all groups of order \\(\\leq 5\\) are commutative. Give an example of a noncommutative group of order \\(6\\)._",
        "Solution": "The trivial group is clearly abelian. Groups of prime order are cyclic, by Lagrange's Theorem [11, pag. 41] and so must be abelian. Hence, groups of orders \\(2\\), \\(3\\), and \\(5\\) are abelian. This leaves only groups of order \\(4\\). Every group of order \\(4\\) can have nontrivial elements of orders \\(2\\) or \\(4\\). If such a group has an element of order \\(4\\), it is cyclic, and so abelian. If every element is of order \\(2\\), it is also abelian, since, given any two elements \\(a\\) and \\(b\\),\n\n\\[abab=(ab)^{2}=1=a^{2}b^{2},\\]\n\nand canceling yields \\(ba=ab\\). The group of symmetries of the triangle, \\(D\\_{3}\\), has \\(6\\) elements and is nonabelian.\n\nSolution to 6.8.5:By the Structure Theorem for finitely generated abelian groups [Her75, pag. 109], there are three: \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{8}\\), \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\), and \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\).\n\n1. \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{15})^{\\star}=\\{1,2,4,7,8,11,13,14\\}\\). By inspection, we see that every element is of order \\(2\\) or \\(4\\). Hence, \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{15})^{\\star}\\simeq\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\)\n2. \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{17})^{\\star}=\\{1,2,\\ldots,16\\}=\\{\\pm 1,\\pm 2,\\ldots,\\pm 8\\}\\), passing to the quotient \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{17})^{\\star}/\\{\\pm 1\\}=\\{1,2,\\ldots,8\\}\\) which is generated by \\(3\\), so \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{17})^{\\star}\\simeq\\mathbb{Z}_{8}\\).\n3. The roots form a cyclic group of order \\(8\\) isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{8}\\).\n4. \\(\\mathbf{F}_{8}\\) is a field of characteristic \\(2\\), so every element added to itself is \\(0\\). Hence, \\[\\mathbf{F}_{8}^{+}\\cong\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times\\mathbb{Z}\\_{2}.\\]\n5. \\((\\mathbb{Z}_{16})^{\\star}=\\{1,3,5,7,9,11,13,15\\}\\cong\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\times \\mathbb{Z}\\_{4}\\).\n\nSolution to 6.8.6:Order 24: The groups \\(S*{4}\\) and \\(S*{3}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\) are nonabelian of order \\(24\\). They are not isomorphic since \\(S_{4}\\) does not contain any element of order \\(24\\) but \\(S*{3}\\times\\mathbb{Z}*{4}\\) does.\n\nOrder 30: The groups \\(D*{3}\\times\\mathbb{Z}*{5}\\) and \\(D*{5}\\times\\mathbb{Z}*{3}\\) have different numbers of Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroups, namely \\(3\\) and \\(5\\), respectively.\n\nOrder 40: There are two examples where the Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroup is normal: The direct product of \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{5}\\) with a nonabelian group of order \\(8\\). Such order \\(8\\) groups are the dihedral group of symmetries of the square (which has only two elements of order \\(4\\)), and the group of the quaternions \\(\\{\\pm 1,\\pm i,\\pm j,\\pm k\\}\\) (which has six elements of order \\(4\\)). There are also several other examples where the Sylow \\(2\\)-subgroup is not normal.\n\nSolution to 6.8.8:The number of Sylow \\(3\\)-subgroups is congruent to \\(1\\) mod \\(3\\) and divides \\(5\\); hence, there is exactly one such subgroup, which is normal in the group. It is an abelian group of order \\(9\\). The abelian groups of this order are the cyclic group of order \\(9\\) and the direct product of two cyclic groups of order \\(3\\).\n\nThe number of Sylow \\(5\\)-subgroups is congruent to \\(1\\) mod \\(5\\) and divides \\(9\\); hence, there is exactly one such subgroup, which is the (normal) cyclic group of order \\(5\\). The Sylow \\(3\\)-subgroup and the Sylow \\(5\\)-subgroup intersect trivially so their direct product is contained in the whole group, and a computation of the order shows that the whole group is exactly this direct product. Therefore, there are, up to isomorphism, two possibilities\n\n\\[\\mathbb{Z}_{9}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{5}\\,\\qquad\\mathbb{Z}_{3}\\times\\mathbb{Z}_{3} \\times\\mathbb{Z}\\_{5}\\.\\]"
    },
    "Problem 6.8.3": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that any group of order \\(6\\) is isomorphic to either \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{6}\\) or \\(S*{3}\\) (the group of permutations of three objects).*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.4": {
        "Problem": "1. _Show that, to within isomorphism, there is just one noncyclic group_ \\(G\\) _of order_ \\(4\\)_._\n2. _Show that the group of automorphisms of_ \\(G\\) _is isomorphic to the permutation group_ \\(S*{3}\\)*.\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.5": {
        "Problem": "_Find all abelian groups of order \\(8\\), up to isomorphism. Then identify which type occurs in each of_\n\n1. \\(\\left(\\mathbb{Z}_{15}\\right)^{\\star}\\)_,\\_\n2. \\(\\left(\\mathbb{Z}_{17}\\right)^{\\star}/(\\pm 1)\\)_,\\_\n3. _the roots of_ \\(z^{8}-1\\) _in_ \\(\\mathbb{C}\\)_,_\n4. \\(\\mathbf{F}_{8}^{+}\\)_,\\_\n5. \\(\\left(\\mathbb{Z}_{16}\\right)^{\\star}\\)_.\\_\n\n\\(\\mathbf{F}_{8}\\) \\_is the field of eight elements, and_ \\(\\mathbf{F}_{8}^{+}\\) \\_is its underlying additive group;_ \\(R^{\\star}\\) _is the group of invertible elements in the ring_ \\(R\\)_, under multiplication._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.7": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that if \\(p\\) is prime then every group of order \\(p^{2}\\) is abelian._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.8": {
        "Problem": "_Classify up to isomorphism all groups of order \\(45\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.9": {
        "Problem": "_Classify abelian groups of order \\(80\\) up to isomorphism._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.10": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(S\\) be a collection of abelian groups, each of order \\(720\\), no two of which are isomorphic. What is the maximum cardinality \\(S\\) can have?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.8.11": {
        "Problem": "_Find (up to isomorphism) all groups of order \\(2p\\), where \\(p\\) is a prime (\\(p\\geq 2\\))._",
        "Solution": "If \\(p=2\\), then the group is either cyclic and so isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{4}\\), or every element has order \\(2\\) and so is abelian and isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\oplus\\mathbb{Z}\\_{2}\\).\n\nNow suppose \\(p>2\\) and let \\(G\\) have order \\(2p\\). By Sylow's Theorems [Her75, pag. 91], the \\(p\\)-Sylow subgroup of \\(G\\) must be normal, since the number of such subgroups must divide \\(2p\\) and be congruent to \\(1\\bmod p\\). Since the \\(p\\)-Sylow subgroup has order \\(p\\), it is cyclic; let it be generated by \\(g\\). A similar argument shows that the number of \\(2\\)-Sylow subgroups is odd and divides \\(2p\\); hence, there is a unique, normal \\(2\\)-Sylow subgroup, or there are \\(p\\) conjugate \\(2\\)-Sylow subgroups. Let one of the \\(2\\)-Sylow subgroups be generated by \\(h\\).\n\nIn the first case, the element \\(ghg^{-1}h^{-1}\\) is in the intersection of the \\(2\\)-Sylow and the \\(p\\)-Sylow subgroups since they are both normal; these are cyclic groups of different orders, so it follows that \\(ghg^{-1}h^{-1}=1\\), or \\(hg=gh\\). Since \\(g\\) and \\(h\\) must generate \\(G\\), we see that \\(G\\) is abelian and isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}\\oplus\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\).\n\nIn the second case, a counting argument shows that all the elements of \\(G\\) can be written in the form \\(g^{i}h^{j}\\), \\(0\\leq i<p\\), \\(0\\leq j<2\\). Since all the elements of the form \\(g^{i}\\) have order \\(p\\), it follows that all the \\(2\\)-Sylow subgroups are generated by the elements \\(g^{i}h\\). Hence, all of these elements are of order \\(2\\); in particular, \\(ghgh=1\\), or \\(hg=g^{-1}h\\). Thus, \\(G=\\langle g,h\\mid g^{p}=h^{2}=1,hg=g^{-1}h\\rangle\\) and so \\(G\\) is the dihedral group \\(D\\_{n}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.8.12": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that any finite group of order \\(n\\) is isomorphic to a subgroup of \\(\\mathbb{O}(n)\\), the group of \\(n\\times n\\) orthogonal real matrices._",
        "Solution": "By Cayley's Theorem [Her75, pag. 71], every group of order \\(n\\) is isomorphic to a subgroup of \\(S*{n}\\), so it is enough to show that \\(S*{n}\\) is isomorphic to a subgroup of \\(\\mathbb{O}(n)\\). For each \\(\\sigma\\in S*{n}\\), consider the matrix \\(A*{\\sigma}=(a*{ij})\\), where \\(a*{\\sigma(i)\\,i}=1\\) and all other entries are zero. Let \\(\\varphi\\) be defined by \\(\\sigma\\mapsto\\varphi(\\sigma)=A*{\\sigma}\\). The matrix \\(A*{\\sigma}\\) has exactly one \\(1\\) in each row and column. Hence, both the rows and columns form an orthonormal basis of \\(\\mathbb{R}^{n}\\), so \\(A*{\\sigma}\\) is orthogonal. \\(\\varphi\\) maps \\(S*{n}\\) into \\(\\mathbb{O}(n)\\). Let \\(A*{\\sigma}=(a*{ij})\\) and \\(B*{\\tau}=(b*{ij})\\). Then\n\n\\[A*{\\sigma}B*{\\tau}=(c*{ij})=\\left(\\sum*{k=1}^{n}a*{ik}b*{kj}\\right).\\]\n\nAn element of this matrix is \\(1\\) if and only if \\(i=\\sigma(k)\\) and \\(k=\\tau(j)\\) for some \\(k\\); equivalently, if and only if \\(i=\\sigma(\\tau(j))\\). Hence, \\(c*{\\sigma(\\tau(i))\\,i}=1\\) and all the other entries are \\(0\\). Therefore, \\((c*{ij})=A\\_{\\sigma\\cdot\\tau}\\), so \\(\\varphi\\) is a homomorphism.\n\nIf \\(A\\_{\\sigma}\\) equals the identity matrix, then \\(\\sigma(i)=i\\) for \\(1\\leq i\\leq n\\), so \\(\\sigma\\) is the identity permutation. Thus, \\(\\varphi\\) has trivial kernel and is one-to-one hence an isomorphism."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(M\\) be the ring of real 2\\(\\times\\)2 matrices and \\(S\\subset M\\) the subring of matrices of the form_\n\n\\[\\left(\\begin{array}{cc}a&-b\\\\ b&a\\end{array}\\right).\\]\n\n1. _Exhibit (without proof) an isomorphism between_ \\(S\\) _and_ \\(\\mathbb{C}\\) _._\n2. _Prove that_ \\[A=\\left(\\begin{array}{cc}0&3\\\\ -4&1\\end{array}\\right)\\] _lies in a subring isomorphic to_ \\(S\\)_._\n3. _Prove that there is an_ \\(X\\in M\\) _such that_ \\(X^{4}+13X=A\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.9.2": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that there exists only one automorphism of the field of real numbers; namely the identity automorphism._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.9.3": {
        "Problem": "_Suppose addition and multiplication are defined on \\(\\mathbb{C}\\,^{n}\\), complex \\(n\\)-space, coordinatewise, making \\(\\mathbb{C}\\,^{n}\\) into a ring. Find all ring homomorphisms of \\(\\mathbb{C}\\,^{n}\\) onto \\(\\mathbb{C}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{C}\\,^{n}\\to\\mathbb{C}\\,\\) be a ring homomorphism and \\(e*{1}=(1,0,0,\\ldots,0),e*{2}=(0,1,0,\\ldots,0),\\ldots,e*{n}=(0,0,0,\\ldots,1)\\), then \\(e*{i}e*{j}=0\\) for all \\(i\\neq j\\) and if \\(\\varphi(e*{1})=\\cdots=\\varphi(e\\_{n})=0\\),\n\n\\[\\varphi(x*{1},\\ldots,x*{n})=\\varphi(x*{1},0,\\ldots,0)\\varphi(e*{1})+\\cdots+ \\varphi(0,0,\\ldots,x*{n})\\varphi(e*{n})=0\\]\n\nthat is, \\(\\varphi\\) is identically zero.\n\nSuppose now that \\(\\varphi\\) is a nontrivial homomorphism, then \\(\\varphi(e*{i})\\neq 0\\) for some \\(i\\) and in this case \\(\\varphi(e*{i})=\\varphi(e*{i}e*{i})=\\varphi(e*{i})\\varphi(e*{i})\\) and \\(\\varphi(e*{i})=1\\). At the same time \\(0=\\varphi(e*{i}e*{j})=\\varphi(e*{i})\\varphi(e*{j})\\) we conclude that \\(\\varphi(e*{j})=0\\) for all \\(j\\neq i\\), and \\(\\varphi\\) is determined by its value on the \\(i^{th}\\) coordinate.\n\n\\[\\varphi(x*{1},\\ldots,x*{i},\\ldots,x*{n}) =\\varphi(0,\\ldots,x*{i},\\ldots,0)\\varphi(e*{i})\\] \\[=\\varphi(0,\\ldots,x*{i},\\ldots,0)1\\] \\[=\\varphi(0,\\ldots,x\\_{i},\\ldots,0)\\]\n\nSo for every homomorphism \\(\\sigma:\\mathbb{C}\\,\\to\\mathbb{C}\\,\\) we can create \\(n\\) such homomorphisms from \\(\\mathbb{C}\\,^{n}\\) to \\(\\mathbb{C}\\,\\) by composing \\(\\varphi(x*{1},\\ldots,x*{n})=\\sigma(\\pi*{i}(x*{1},\\ldots,x*{n}))\\) where \\(\\pi*{i}\\) is the projection on the \\(i^{th}\\) coordinate, and the argument above shows that all arise in this way."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a finite ring. Prove that there are positive integers m and n with \\(m>n\\) such that \\(x^{m}=x^{n}\\) for every x in \\(R\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(R\\) contain \\(k\\) elements (\\(k<\\infty\\)) and consider the ring\n\n\\[S=\\underbrace{R\\times R\\times\\cdots\\times R}_{k\\text{ copies}}\\]Let \\(R=\\{r_{1},\\ldots,r*{k}\\}\\) and \\(\\alpha=(r*{1},\\ldots,r*{k})\\in S\\). Now consider the collection of elements \\(\\alpha\\), \\(\\alpha^{2}\\), \\(\\alpha^{3},\\ldots\\). Since \\(S\\) is also a finite ring, by the Pigeon-hole Principle [Her75, pag. 127], there exist \\(n\\) and \\(m\\) sufficiently large with \\(\\alpha^{n}=\\alpha^{m}\\). Coordinatewise, this means that \\(r*{i}^{n}=r\\_{i}^{m}\\) for \\(1\\leq i\\leq k\\), and we are done."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a ring with at least two elements. Suppose that for each nonzero \\(a\\) in \\(R\\) there is a unique \\(b\\) in \\(R\\) (depending on \\(a\\)) with \\(aba=a\\). Show that \\(R\\) is a division ring._\n\n_Hint: Show first that \\(R\\) has no zero divisors, then find a multiplicative indentity in \\(R\\), then prove the existence of inverses._",
        "Solution": "If \\(ax=0\\) (or \\(xa=0\\)) with \\(a\\neq 0\\), then \\(axa=0a\\) or \\(a0=0\\). If \\(b\\) is as in the text, then \\(a(b+x)a=a\\), so, by uniqueness of \\(b\\), \\(b=b+x\\) and \\(x=0\\). Thus, there are no zero divisors.\n\nFix \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) such that \\(aba=a\\). If \\(x\\in R\\), then \\(xaba=xa\\) and, as there are no zero divisors, \\(xab=x\\), so \\(ab\\) is a right identity. Similarly, \\(abax=ax\\) implies \\(bax=x\\) and \\(ba\\) is a left identity. Since any right identity is equal to any right identity, we get \\(ab=ba=1\\). Since \\(b=a^{-1}\\), \\(R\\) is a division ring."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.6": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(p\\) be a prime number and \\(R\\) a ring with identity containing \\(p^{2}\\) elements. Prove that \\(R\\) is commutative._",
        "Solution": "Since \\((R,+)\\) is a finite abelian group with \\(p^{2}\\) elements, by the Structure Theorem for finite abelian groups [Her75, pag. 109], it is isomorphic to either \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p^{2}}\\) or \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\oplus\\mathbb{Z}\\_{p}\\). In the first case, there is an element \\(x\\in R\\) such that every element of \\(R\\) can be written as \\(nx\\), for \\(1\\leq n\\leq p^{2}\\). Since all elements of this form commute, it follows that \\(R\\) is abelian.\n\nIn the second case, every nonzero element must have additive order \\(p\\). Let \\(x\\in R\\) be any element not in the additive subgroup generated by \\(1\\). Then it too must have additive order \\(p\\). Thus, a counting argument shows that every element of \\(R\\) can be written in the form \\(n+kx\\), \\(1\\leq n\\leq p\\), \\(1\\leq k\\leq p\\). Since all elements of this form commute, it follows that \\(R\\) is commutative."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a commutative ring with identity. Let \\(G\\) be a finite subgroup of \\(R^{\\star}\\), the group of units of \\(R\\). Prove that if \\(R\\) is an integral domain, then \\(G\\) is cyclic._",
        "Solution": "One can embed \\(R\\) in the field of quotients of \\(R\\); then the finite subgroup of \\(R^{\\*}\\) is a finite subgroup of the multiplicative group of the field; it is a finite abelian group, and so can be written as a direct product of \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{p^{n}}\\) for various primes \\(p\\). If there are two such factors for the same \\(p\\), then there are at least \\(p\\) elements of the field satisfying the equation \\(x^{p}-1=0\\). However, in a field, due to the uniqueness of factorization in the polynomial ring, there are, at most, \\(n\\) solutions to any \\(n^{th}\\) degree polynomial equation in one variable. Thus, in the factorization of our group, each prime \\(p\\) occurs at most once, therefore, any such group is cyclic."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a ring with an identity, and let \\(u\\) be an element of \\(R\\) with a right inverse. Prove that the following conditions on \\(u\\) are equivalent:_\n\n1. \\(u\\) _has more than one right inverse;_\n2. \\(u\\) _is a zero divisor;_\n3. \\(u\\) _is not a unit._",
        "Solution": "\\(1\\Rightarrow 2\\) : There exist \\(v*{1}\\neq v*{2}\\) such that \\(uv*{1}=uv*{2}=1\\); thus, \\(u(v*{1}-v*{2})=0\\) and \\(u\\) is a zero divisor.\n\n\\(2\\Rightarrow 3\\) : Suppose that \\(u\\) is a unit with inverse \\(v\\). If the \\(uv=0\\) then \\(w=(vu)w=v(uw)=v0=0\\) and, therefore, \\(u\\) is not a left zero divisor.\n\n\\(3\\Rightarrow 1\\) : Let \\(v\\) be a right inverse for \\(u\\), that is, \\(uv=1\\). Since \\(u\\) is not a unit \\(vu\\neq 1\\) implying \\(vu-1\\neq 0\\). Now consider the element \\(v^{\\prime}=v+(vu-1)\\neq v\\), and we have\n\n\\[uv^{\\prime}=uv+u(vu-1)\\]\\[=1-(uv)u-u\\] \\[=1+u-u=1\\]\n\nshowing that \\(u\\) has more than one right inverse."
    },
    "Problem 6.9.10": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(D\\) be an ordered integral domain and \\(a\\in D\\). Prove that_\n\n\\[a^{2}-a+1>0.\\]",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.9.11": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x,y\\right]/\\langle x^{2}+y^{2}-1\\rangle\\) is an integral domain and that its field of fractions is isomorphic to the field of rational functions \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(t\\right)\\)._\n\n### Ideals",
        "Solution": "The degree-\\(2\\) polynomial \\(x^{2}+y^{2}-1\\) does not factor into the product of two linear ones (since the circle \\(x^{2}+y^{2}=1\\) is not a union of two lines). This implies that the ideal \\(\\langle x^{2}+y^{2}-1\\rangle\\) is prime and, thus, the ring \\(R=\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x,y\\right]/\\langle x^{2}+y^{2}-1\\rangle\\) is an integral domain.\n\nConsider now the _stereographic projection_\\((x,y)\\mapsto(1,y/(x+1))\\) (at half of the speed of the standard one, in order to make the expressions simpler) of the circle from the point (-1,0) to the line \\((1,t)\\). It provides a homomorphism \\(t=y/(x+1)\\) of \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(t\\right)\\) to the field of fractions of \\(R\\). The inverse homomorphism is given by the formulas \\(x=(1-t^{2})/(1+t^{2})\\) and \\(y=2t/(1+t^{2})\\).\n\n### 6.10 Ideals"
    },
    "Problem 6.10.1": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(A\\) be the ring of real 2\\(\\times\\)2 matrices of the form \\(\\left(\\begin{smallmatrix}a&b\\\\ 0&c\\end{smallmatrix}\\right)\\). What are the 2-sided ideals in \\(A\\)? Justify your answer._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.10.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a field and let \\(X\\) be a finite set. Let \\(R(X,\\mathbf{F})\\) be the ring of all functions from \\(X\\) to \\(\\mathbf{F}\\), endowed with the pointwise operations. What are the maximal ideals of \\(R(X,\\mathbf{F})\\)?_",
        "Solution": "Each element of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) induces a constant function on \\(X\\), and we identify the function with the element of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\). In particular, the function \\(1\\) is the unit element in \\(R(X,\\mathbf{F})\\).\n\nLet \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) be a proper ideal of \\(R(X,\\mathbf{F})\\). We will prove that there is a nonempty subset \\(Y\\) of \\(X\\) such that \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\{f\\in R(X,\\mathbf{F})\\,|\\,f(x)=0\\ \\forall x\\in Y\\}=\\mathfrak{I}_{Y}\\). Suppose not. Then either \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}_{Y}\\) for some set \\(Y\\) or, for every point \\(x\\in X\\), there is a function \\(f*{x}\\) in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) such that \\(f*{x}(x)=a\\neq 0\\). In the latter case, since \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) is an ideal and \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) is a field, we can replace \\(f*{x}\\) by the function \\(a^{-1}f*{x}\\), so we may assume that \\(f*{x}(x)=1\\). Multiplying \\(f*{x}\\) by the function \\(g*{x}\\), which maps \\(x\\) to \\(1\\) and all other points of \\(X\\) to \\(0\\), we see that \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) contains \\(g*{x}\\) for all points \\(x\\in X\\). But then, since \\(X\\) is finite, \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) contains \\(\\sum g\\_{x}\\equiv 1\\), which implies that \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) is not a proper ideal.\n\nHence, there is a nonempty set \\(Y\\) such that \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}_{Y}\\). Let \\(Y\\) be the largest such set. As for every \\(x\\not\\in Y\\), there is an \\(f_{x}\\in\\mathfrak{I}\\) such that \\(f*{x}(x)\\neq 0\\) (otherwise we would have \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}*{Y\\cup\\{x\\}}\\)) by an argument similar to the above, \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) contains all the functions \\(g*{x}\\), \\(x\\not\\in Y\\). But, from these, we can construct any function in \\(\\mathfrak{I}*{Y}\\), so \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\_{Y}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}\\).\n\nLet \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) be two ideals, and the associated sets be \\(Y\\) and \\(Z\\). Then \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}\\) if and only if \\(Z\\subset Y\\). Therefore, an ideal is maximal if and only if its associated set is as small as possible without being empty. Hence, the maximal ideals are precisely those ideals consisting of functions which vanish at one point of \\(X\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) be a commutative ring with unit element and \\(a\\in R\\). Let \\(n\\) and \\(m\\) be positive integers, and write \\(d=\\gcd\\{n,m\\}\\). Prove that the ideal of \\(R\\) generated by \\(a^{n}-1\\) and \\(a^{m}-1\\) is the same as the ideal generated by \\(a^{d}-1\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\langle a^{n}-1,a^{m}-1\\rangle\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\langle a^{d}-1\\rangle\\). For \\(n=rd\\) the polynomial \\(x^{n}-1\\) factors into \\((x^{d}-1)(x^{r(d-1)}+x^{r(d-2)}+\\cdots+x^{r}+1)\\). Therefore, in \\(R\\), \\(a^{n}-1=(a^{d}-1)(a^{r(d-1)}+a^{r(d-2)}+\\cdots+a^{r}+1)\\). A similar identity holds for \\(a^{m}-1\\). Hence, the two generators of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) are in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), so \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}\\).\n\nSince \\(d=\\gcd\\{n,m\\}\\), there exist positive integers \\(x\\) and \\(y\\) such that \\(xn-ym=d\\). A calculation gives\n\n\\[a^{d}-1 =a^{d}-1-a^{d+ym}+a^{xn}\\] \\[=-a^{d}(a^{ym}-1)+a^{xn}-1\\] \\[=-a^{d}(a^{m}-1)(a^{y(m-1)}+\\cdots+a^{y}+1)\\] \\[\\quad+(a^{n}-1)(a^{x(n-1)}+\\cdots+a^{x}+1).\\]\n\nHence, \\(a^{d}-1\\) is in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), so \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathfrak{I}\\) and the two ideals are equal."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.6": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(R\\) _be a commutative ring with_ \\(1\\) _containing an element_ \\(a\\) _with_ \\(a^{3}=a+1\\)_. Further, let_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _be an ideal of_ \\(R\\) _of index_ \\(<5\\) _in_ \\(R\\)_. Prove that_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}=R\\)_._\n2. _Show that there exists a commutative ring with_ \\(1\\) _that has an element_ \\(a\\) _with_ \\(a^{3}=a+1\\) _and that contains an ideal of index_ \\(5\\)_._\n\n_Note: The term index is used here exactly as in group theory; namely the index of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) in \\(R\\) means the order of \\(R/\\mathfrak{I}\\)._",
        "Solution": "1. If there is an ideal \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\neq R\\) of index, at most, \\(4\\), then there is also a maximal ideal of index, at most, \\(4\\), \\(\\mathfrak{M}\\), say. Then \\(R/\\mathfrak{M}\\) is a field of cardinality less than \\(5\\) containing an element \\(\\alpha\\) with \\(\\alpha^{3}=\\alpha+1\\), namely \\(\\alpha=a+\\mathfrak{M}\\). By direct inspection, we see that none of the fields \\(\\mathbf{F}_{2}\\), \\(\\mathbf{F}_{3}\\), \\(\\mathbf{F}\\_{4}\\) contains such an element. Therefore, \\(\\mathfrak{I}=R\\).\n\n2. Let \\(R=\\mathbb{Z}\\_{5}\\), \\(a=2\\) (mod \\(5\\)), and \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\{0\\}\\).\n\n_Solution 2._ Since \\(R/\\mathfrak{I}\\) has order less than \\(5\\), two of the elements \\(0,1,a,a^{2},a^{3}\\) have the same image in \\(R/\\mathfrak{I}\\). Then \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) contains one of their differences, that is, one of\n\n\\[1\\,,\\,a\\,,\\,a^{2}\\,,\\,a^{3}\\,,\\,a-1\\,,\\,a^{2}-1\\,,\\,a^{3}-1\\,,\\,a(a-a)\\,,\\,a(a ^{2}-1)\\,,\\,a^{2}(a-1).\\]But all these elements are units, since\n\n\\[a(a-1)(a+1)=a(a^{2}-1)=1,\\qquad a^{3}-1=a.\\]\n\nTherefore, \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) contains a unit, so \\(\\mathfrak{I}=R\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.7": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(R\\) _be a commutative ring with_ \\(1\\)_, and_ \\(R^{_}\\) *be its group of units. Suppose that the additive group of* \\(R\\) *is generated by* \\(\\{u^{2}\\mid u\\in R^{_}\\}\\)_. Prove that_ \\(R\\) _has, at most, one ideal_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _for which_ \\(R/\\mathfrak{I}\\) _has cardinality_ \\(3\\)_._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) be such an ideal. Consider \\(\\varphi:R\\to R/\\mathfrak{I}\\), the quotient map. Since \\(R/\\mathfrak{I}\\) is a three element ring with \\(1\\), it must be isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{3}\\). If \\(u\\in R^{\\*}\\) is a unit then so is \\(\\varphi(u)\\). Hence, \\(\\varphi(u)=\\pm 1\\), and \\(\\varphi(u^{2})=1\\). As the squares of the units generate the additive group of \\(R\\), this uniquely determines \\(\\varphi\\) so there is, at most, one such \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.8": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(R\\) _be a ring with_ \\(1\\)_, and let_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _be the left ideal of_ \\(R\\) _generated by_ \\(\\{ab-ba\\mid a,b\\in R\\}\\)_. Prove that_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _is a two-sided ideal._",
        "Solution": "It suffices to show that if \\(ab-ba\\) is any generator of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) and if \\(c\\) is any element of \\(R\\), then \\(abc-bac\\) is in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\). By the definition of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), \\(a(bc)-(bc)a\\) is an element of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\). Further, since \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) is a left ideal, \\(b(ca-ac)=bca-bac\\) is an element of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\). Therefore, \\(abc-bac=abc-bca+bca-bac\\) is in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), and we are done."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.9": {
        "Problem": "1. _Suppose that_ \\(R\\) _is a subring of a commutative ring_ \\(S\\) _and that_ \\(R\\) _is of finite index_ \\(n\\) _in_ \\(S\\)_. Let_ \\(m\\) _be an integer that is relatively prime to_ \\(n\\)_. Prove that the natural map_ \\(R/mR\\to S/mS\\) _is a ring isomorphism._",
        "Solution": "The fact that this map is a ring homomorphism follows from the fact that the inclusion map \\(R\\to S\\) is a ring homomorphism mapping \\(mR\\) into \\(mS\\). Let \\(1=an+bm\\), with integers \\(a\\), \\(b\\). Let \\(r\\in R\\) be in the kernel. Then \\(r=ms\\) for some \\(s\\in S\\), so \\(r=(am+bn)r=m(ar+bns)\\). Since \\(R\\) has index \\(n\\) in \\(S\\), we have \\(ns\\in R\\) and so \\(r\\in mR\\). This shows that the map is an injection. Now suppose \\(s\\in S\\). Then \\(s=(am+bn)s\\equiv b(ns)\\bmod mS\\). As \\(ns\\in R\\), the map is a surjection."
    },
    "Problem 6.10.10": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(\\mathbf{M}\\) _be one of the following fields:_ \\(\\mathbb{R}\\)_,_ \\(\\mathbb{C}\\) _,_ \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\) _, and_ \\(\\mathbf{F}_{9}\\) _(the field with nine elements). Let* \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\subset\\mathbf{M}[x]\\) \\_be the ideal generated by* \\(x^{4}+2x-2\\)_. For which choices of_ \\(\\mathbf{M}\\) _is the ring_ \\(\\mathbf{M}[x]/\\mathfrak{I}\\) _a field?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.10.11": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(R\\) _be a principal ideal domain and let_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _and_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) _be nonzero ideals in_ \\(R\\)_. Show that_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\mathfrak{I}=\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\mathfrak{I}\\) _if and only if_ \\(\\mathfrak{I}+\\mathfrak{I}=R\\)_._\n\n### Polynomials",
        "Solution": "We have \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\langle i\\rangle\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{I}=\\langle j\\rangle\\), for some \\(i,j\\in R\\). Suppose first that \\(\\mathfrak{I}+\\mathfrak{I}=R\\). Then \\(1\\in\\mathfrak{I}+\\mathfrak{I}\\), so \\(1=ri+sj\\) for some \\(r,s\\in R\\). Therefore, the greatest common divisor of \\(i\\) and \\(j\\) is \\(1\\). Now \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\mathfrak{I}\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\mathfrak{I}\\) are both ideals and, clearly, have generators \\(ij\\) and \\(k\\), respectively, where \\(k\\) is the least common multiple of \\(i\\) and \\(j\\). But the greatest common divisor of \\(i\\) and \\(j\\) is \\(1\\), so \\(ij=k\\), and \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\mathfrak{I}=\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\mathfrak{I}\\). Since every implication in the previous argument can be reversed, if \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\mathfrak{I}=\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\ \\mathfrak{I}\\), then \\(\\mathfrak{I}+\\mathfrak{I}=R\\) and we are done.\n\n### 6.11 Polynomials"
    },
    "Problem 6.11.1": {
        "Problem": "1. _By the Fundamental Theorem of Algebra, the polynomial_ \\(x^{3}+2x^{2}+7x+1\\) _has three complex roots,_ \\(\\alpha*{1}\\)*,_ \\(\\alpha_{2}\\)_, and_ \\(\\alpha*{3}\\)*. Compute* \\(\\alpha*{1}^{3}+\\alpha*{2}^{3}+\\alpha*{3}^{3}\\)_._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.2": {
        "Problem": "1. _Suppose the complex number_ \\(\\alpha\\) _is a root of a polynomial of degree_ \\(n\\) _with rational coefficients. Prove that_ \\(1/\\alpha\\) _is also a root of a polynomial of degree_ \\(n\\) _with rational coefficients._",
        "Solution": "If \\(P(z)\\) is a polynomial of degree \\(n\\) with \\(\\alpha\\) as a root, then \\(z^{n}P(1/z)\\) is a polynomial of degree \\(n\\) with \\(1/\\alpha\\) as a root."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.3": {
        "Problem": "1. _Let_ \\(\\zeta=e^{\\frac{2\\pi i}{\\zeta}}\\) _be a primitive_ \\(7^{th}\\) _root of unity. Find a cubic polynomial with integer coefficients having_ \\(\\alpha=\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1}\\) _as a root._",
        "Solution": "Since \\(\\zeta\\) is a primitive seventh root of unity, we have\n\n\\[\\zeta^{6}+\\zeta^{5}+\\cdots+\\zeta+1=0.\\]\n\nDividing this by \\(\\zeta^{3}\\), we get\n\n\\[(\\zeta^{3}+\\zeta^{-3})+(\\zeta^{2}+\\zeta^{-2})+(\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1})+1=0.\\]As \\((\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1})^{2}=(\\zeta^{2}+\\zeta^{-2})+2\\) and \\((\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1})^{3}=(\\zeta^{3}+\\zeta^{-3})+3(\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1})\\), the above equation becomes, letting \\(\\alpha=(\\zeta+\\zeta^{-1})\\),\n\n\\[\\alpha^{3}+\\alpha^{2}-2\\alpha-1=0.\\]"
    },
    "Problem 6.11.5": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that \\(\\sqrt{2}+\\sqrt[3]{3}\\) is irrational._",
        "Solution": "It is easy to see that \\(\\sqrt{2}+\\sqrt[3]{3}\\) is a zero of a monic polynomial \\(p\\in\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) (use the process described on Problem 6.11.4.) If it were a rational number, it would have to be an integer, since its denominator would divide the leading coefficient of \\(p\\). As \\(\\sqrt{2}+\\sqrt[3]{3}\\) is strictly between 2 and 3, it must be irrational.\n\n_Solution 2._ Suppose \\(\\sqrt{2}+\\sqrt[3]{3}\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\). Then \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(\\sqrt{2}\\right)=\\mathbb{Q}\\left(\\sqrt[3]{3}\\right)\\). However, this contradicts the fact that the fields \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(\\sqrt{2}\\right)\\) and \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(\\sqrt[3]{3}\\right)\\) have degrees 2 and 3 over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\), respectively, since by Eisenstein Criterion [10, pag. 160], the polynomials \\(x^{2}-2\\) and \\(x^{3}-3\\) are irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.6": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(P(z)\\) be a polynomial of degree \\(<k\\) with complex coefficients. Let \\(\\omega_{1},\\ldots,\\omega*{k}\\) be the \\(k^{th}\\) roots of unity in \\(\\mathbb{C}\\). Prove that*\n\n\\[\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{i=1}^{k}P(\\omega*{i})=P(0).\\]",
        "Solution": "Suppose that \\(\\omega\\) is a primitive \\(k^{th}\\) root of unity and that \\(\\omega*{i}=\\omega^{i}\\) for \\(1\\leq i\\leq k\\). Let \\(P(z)=a*{0}+a*{1}z+\\cdots+a*{j}z^{j}\\) (\\(j<k\\)); we have\n\n\\[\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{i=1}^{k}P(\\omega^{i})=\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{i=1}^{k}\\sum*{r=0}^{j} a*{r}\\omega^{ir}=\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{r=0}^{j}a*{r}\\sum\\_{i=1}^{k}\\omega^{ir}\\]Since \\(\\omega^{k}=1\\), we have \\(\\omega^{rk}-1=0\\) for \\(1\\leq r\\leq j\\). Factoring and replacing \\(1\\) by \\(\\omega^{rk}\\), we get\n\n\\[0=(\\omega^{r}-1)(\\omega^{rk}+\\omega^{r(k-1)}+\\cdots+\\omega^{r}).\\]\n\nSince \\(r<k\\) and \\(\\omega\\) is a primitive root of unity, \\(\\omega^{r}\\neq 1\\). Therefore,\n\n\\[\\omega^{rk}+\\omega^{r(k-1)}+\\cdots+\\omega^{r}=0.\\]\n\nSubstituting this into the above equality gives\n\n\\[\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{i=1}^{k}P(\\omega^{i})=\\frac{1}{k}\\sum*{i=1}^{k}a*{0}\\omega^{0 i}=a*{0}=P(0).\\]"
    },
    "Problem 6.11.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(f(x)\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\) be a polynomial with rational coefficients. Show that there is a \\(g(x)\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\), \\(g\\neq\\ 0\\), such that \\(f(x)g(x)=a_{2}x^{2}+a*{3}x^{3}+a*{5}x^{5}+\\cdots+a*{p}x^{p}\\) is a polynomial in which only prime exponents appear.*",
        "Solution": "By the Euclidean Algorithm, the vector space \\(V=\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]/\\langle f\\rangle\\) has dimension \\(d=\\deg(f)\\). Therefore, the infinitely many equivalence classes\n\n\\[\\bar{x}^{2},\\bar{x}^{3},\\bar{x}^{5},\\ldots\\]\n\nare linearly dependent in \\(V\\), so we can let \\(q\\_{i}\\) be a finite collection of rational numbers not all zero and satisfying\n\n\\[q*{2}\\bar{x}^{2}+q*{3}\\bar{x}^{3}+q\\_{5}\\bar{x}^{5}+\\cdots=0.\\]\n\nThis means that\n\n\\[q*{2}x^{2}+q*{3}x^{3}+q\\_{5}x^{5}+\\cdots=f(x)g(x)\\]\n\nfor some nonzero \\(g\\in Q[x]\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) be the ideal in the ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) generated by \\(x-7\\) and \\(15\\). Prove that the quotient ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]/\\mathfrak{I}\\) is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{15}\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "First, note that each polynomial \\(p(x)\\) in \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) is congruent modulo \\(x-7\\) to a unique integer, namely the remainder one obtains by using the division algorithm to divide \\(x-7\\) into \\(p(x)\\). (Only integer coefficients arise in the process, because the coefficient of \\(x\\) in \\(x-7\\) is \\(1\\).) If \\(p(x)\\) lies in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), then so does the preceding remainder. However, the only members of \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\mathbb{Z}\\) are the integers that are divisible by \\(15\\). In fact, if \\(k\\) is in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\cap\\mathbb{Z}\\), say \\(k=(x-7)q(x)+15r(x)\\), then \\(k=15r(7)\\). Hence, we get a well defined map from \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]/\\mathfrak{I}\\) into \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{15}\\) by sending \\(p(x)+\\mathfrak{I}\\) to \\(k+15\\mathbb{Z}\\), where \\(k\\) is the remainder one gets when dividing \\(p(x)\\) by \\(x-7\\). The map is clearly a homomorphism. If \\(p(x)\\) is not a unit in \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\), then the remainder is clearly not divisible by \\(15\\), from which we conclude that the map is one-to-one. The map is obviously surjective. It is, thus, the required isomorphism.\n\n_Solution 2._ The map \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\rightarrow\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) defined by \\(\\varphi\\left(p(x)\\right)=p(x+7)\\) is a ring automorphism and it maps \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) onto the ideal generated by \\(x\\) and \\(15\\). The quotient ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]/\\varphi(\\mathfrak{I})\\) is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{15}\\) under the map \\(p(x)\\mapsto p(0)+15\\mathbb{Z}\\), implying the desired conclusion."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.9": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) denote the ideal in \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\), the ring of polynomials with coefficients in \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\), generated by \\(x^{3}+x+1\\) and \\(5\\). Is \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) a prime ideal?_",
        "Solution": "\\(\\mathfrak{J}\\) is prime. To show this we will prove that the quotient ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]/\\mathfrak{J}\\) is a field. Since \\(5\\in\\mathfrak{J}\\), this quotient ring is isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{5}[x]/\\langle x^{3}+x+1\\rangle\\). So it suffices to show that \\(x^{3}+x+1\\) is irreducible (mod 5). If it were reducible, it would have a linear factor, and, hence, a zero. But we can evaluate this polynomial for each \\(x\\in\\mathbb{Z}_{5}\\) as follows:\n\n\\[\\begin{array}{c|c}x&x^{3}+x+1\\\\ \\hline\\\\ 0&1\\\\ 1&3\\\\ 2&1\\\\ 3&1\\\\ 4&4\\end{array}\\]\n\nSince there is no zero, the polynomial is irreducible, and the quotient ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{5}[x]/\\langle x^{3}+x+1\\rangle\\) is a field."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.10": {
        "Problem": "_In the ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) of polynomials in one variable over the integers, show that the ideal \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) generated by \\(5\\) and \\(x^{2}+2\\) is a maximal ideal._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.11": {
        "Problem": "_let \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\) denote the ring of integers modulo n. Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}[x]\\) be the ring of polynomials with coefficients in \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\). Let \\(\\mathfrak{I}\\) denote the ideal in \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}[x]\\) generated by \\(x^{2}+x+1\\)._\n\n1. _For which values of n,_ \\(1\\leq n\\leq 10\\)_, is the quotient ring_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}[x]/\\mathfrak{I}\\) \\_a field?_\n2. _Give the multiplication table for_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{2}/\\mathfrak{I}\\)_.\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\) be the ring of integers, \\(p\\) a prime, and \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}=\\mathbb{Z}/p\\mathbb{Z}\\) the field of \\(p\\) elements. Let \\(x\\) be an indeterminate, and set \\(R*{1}=\\mathbf{F}*{p}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-2\\rangle\\), \\(R*{2}=\\mathbf{F}*{p}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-3\\rangle\\). Determine whether the rings \\(R*{1}\\) and \\(R*{2}\\) are isomorphic in each of the cases \\(p=2,5,11\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "Case 1: \\(p=2\\). In this case, define a map of \\(\\mathbf{F}_{2}[x]\\) into itself by \\(\\varphi(1)=1\\) and \\(\\varphi(x)=x+1\\), and extend it in the obvious way. Since constants are fixed and \\(\\varphi(x+1)=x\\), it is clear that this is a ring isomorphism. Further, \\(\\varphi(x^{2}-2)=(x-1)^{2}-2=x^{2}+1=x^{2}-3\\); we see that \\(\\varphi\\) maps the ideal \\(\\langle x^{2}-2\\rangle\\) onto the ideal \\(\\langle x^{2}-3\\rangle\\). It follows immediately from this that the two rings \\(\\mathbf{F}_{2}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-2\\rangle\\) and \\(\\mathbf{F}\\_{2}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-3\\rangle\\) are isomorphic.\n\nCase 2: \\(p=5\\). By checking all the elements of \\(\\mathbf{F}_{5}\\), we see that \\(x^{2}-2\\) and \\(x^{2}-3\\) are both irreducible polynomials in \\(\\mathbf{F}_{5}[x]\\). Therefore, the ideals they generate are maximal and the quotient rings \\(\\mathbf{F}_{5}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-2\\rangle\\) and \\(\\mathbf{F}_{5}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-3\\rangle\\) are fields. The Euclidean Algorithm [Her75, pag. 155] shows that each is a finite field with 25 elements. Since finite fields of the same order are isomorphic, the quotient rings in this case are isomorphic.\n\nCase 3: \\(p=11\\). In this case, checking all the elements of \\(\\mathbf{F}_{11}\\) shows that \\(x^{2}-2\\) is irreducible, but \\(x^{2}-3=(x-5)(x+5)\\) is not. Hence, the quotient ring \\(\\mathbf{F}_{11}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-2\\rangle\\) is a field, whereas \\(\\mathbf{F}\\_{11}[x]/\\langle x^{2}-3\\rangle\\) is not, so the two quotient rings are not isomorphic in this case."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.14": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) be the ring of polynomials in the indeterminate \\(x\\) with coefficients in the ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\) of integers. Let \\(\\mathcal{I}\\subset\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) be the ideal generated by \\(13\\) and \\(x\\dashrightarrow 4\\). Find an integer \\(m\\) such that \\(0\\leq m\\leq 12\\) and_\n\n\\[(x^{26}+x+1)^{73}-m\\in\\mathcal{I}\\.\\]",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\to\\mathbb{Z}\\_{13}\\) be the unique ring homomorphism such that \\(\\varphi(x)=4\\). A polynomial \\(\\alpha(x)\\in\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) is in the kernel of \\(\\varphi\\) if and only if \\(\\alpha(4)\\equiv 0\\pmod{13}\\). This occurs if and only if \\(\\alpha(x)\\equiv(x-4)\\beta(x)\\pmod{13}\\) for some \\(\\beta(x)\\in\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\), i.e., exactly when \\(\\alpha(x)=(x-4)\\beta(x)+13\\gamma(x)\\) for some \\(\\gamma(x)\\in\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\), in other words if and only if \\(\\alpha(x)\\in\\mathfrak{I}\\).\n\nSet \\(f(x)=(x^{26}+x+1)^{73}\\in\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\); then \\(f(x)-m\\in\\mathfrak{I}\\) if and only if \\(\\varphi(f(x)-m)=0\\), which holds if and only if \\(f(4)\\equiv m\\pmod{13}\\).\n\nBy Fermat's Little Theorem [10, pag. 80], [11, pag. 44], if \\(a\\in\\mathbb{Z}\\) is not divisible by the prime \\(p\\) then \\(a^{p-1}\\equiv 1\\pmod{p}\\). This gives \\((4^{26}+4+1)\\equiv(4^{2}+5)\\equiv 8\\pmod{13}\\), and \\(f(4)\\equiv 8^{73}\\equiv 8\\pmod{13}\\). So \\(m=8\\) is the unique integer in the range \\(0\\leq m\\leq 12\\) such that \\((x^{26}+x+1)^{73}-m\\in\\mathfrak{I}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.15": {
        "Problem": "1. _In_ \\(\\mathbb{R}[x]\\)_, consider the set of polynomials_ \\(f(x)\\) _for which_ \\(f(2)=f^{\\prime}(2)=f^{\\prime\\prime}(2)=0\\)_. Prove that this set forms an ideal and find its monic generator._\n2. _Do the polynomials such that_ \\(f(2)=0\\) _and_ \\(f^{\\prime}(3)=0\\) _form an ideal?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.16": {
        "Problem": "_Find all automorphisms of \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\), the ring of polynomials over \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\to\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) be any automorphism. Since \\(\\varphi\\) is determined by the value of \\(x\\), every element of \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) must be a polynomial in \\(\\varphi(x)\\). In order to get \\(x\\) in the image of \\(\\varphi\\), we see that \\(\\varphi(x)\\) must be of the form \\(\\pm x+\\alpha\\) for some constant \\(\\alpha\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.17": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(R\\) denote the ring of polynomials over a field \\(\\mathbb{F}\\). Let \\(p_{1},\\ldots,p*{n}\\) be elements of \\(R\\). Prove that the greatest common divisor of \\(p*{1},\\ldots,p*{n}\\) is \\(1\\) if and only if there is an \\(n\\times n\\) matrix over \\(R\\) of determinant \\(1\\) whose first row is \\((p*{1},\\ldots,p*{n})\\).*",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.18": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(f(x)\\) be a polynomial over \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\), the field of integers mod \\(p\\). Let \\(g(x)=x^{p}-x\\). Show that the greatest common divisor of \\(f(x)\\) and \\(g(x)\\) is the product of the distinct linear factors of \\(f(x)\\).\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.19": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) be a subfield of a field \\(\\mathbb{K}\\). Let \\(p\\) and \\(q\\) be polynomials over \\(\\mathbb{F}\\). Prove that their \\(\\gcd\\) (greatest common divisor) in the ring of polynomials over \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is the same as their \\(\\gcd\\) in the ring of polynomials over \\(\\mathbb{K}\\)._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.21": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\) be the ring of integers and \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\) the polynomial ring over \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\). Show that_\n\n\\[x^{6}+539x^{5}-511x+847\\]\n\n_is irreducible in \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\)._",
        "Solution": "Note that \\(539=7^{2}\\cdot 11\\), \\(511=7\\cdot 23\\), and \\(847=7\\cdot 11^{2}\\). Thus, all the coefficients except the leading one are divisible by \\(7\\), but the constant term is not divisible by \\(7^{2}\\). Since \\(7\\) is a prime, by Eisenstein Criterion [11, pag. 160], the polynomial is irreducible in \\(\\mathbb{Z}[x]\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.22": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that the polynomial \\(x^{4}+x+1\\) is irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\)._",
        "Solution": "By the Gauss Lemma [1, pag. 85], an integral polynomial that can be factored over rationals can be factored into polynomials of the same degree over the integers. Since \\(\\pm 1\\) are not roots (and they are the only ones possible because \\(a*{0}=a*{n}=1\\)), there are no linear terms and the only possible factorizations are in polynomials of degree \\(2\\).\n\n- \\((x^{2}+ax+1)(x^{2}+bx+1)\\)\n- \\((x^{2}+ax-1)(x^{2}+bx-1)\\)\n\nIn the first, case we get \\(x^{4}+(a+b)x^{3}+(2+ab)x^{2}+(a+b)x+1\\), which implies that the coefficients of the terms of degree \\(1\\) and \\(3\\), are the same, a contradiction. The other case is analogous, showing that the polynomial is irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.24": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that \\(f(x)=x^{4}+x^{3}+x^{2}+6x+1\\) is irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Put \\(x=y+1\\) to get\n\n\\[f(x)=\\frac{x^{5}-1}{x-1}+5x=\\frac{(y+1)^{5}-1}{y}+5y+5.\\]\n\nThe coefficients of \\(y^{3}\\), \\(y^{2}\\), \\(y\\), and \\(1\\) are integers divisible by \\(p=5\\) and the constant term is \\(10\\), which is not divisible by \\(p^{2}\\). Thus, by Eisenstein Criterion [10, pag. 160], \\(f\\) is irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.25": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{3}\\) be the field of integers \\(\\bmod 3\\) and \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{3}[x]\\) the corresponding polynomial ring. Decompose \\(x^{3}+x+2\\) into irreducible factors in \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{3}[x]\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "Let \\(f(x)=x^{3}+x+2\\). A calculation shows that \\(2\\) is a zero of \\(f(x)\\) over \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{3}\\), but \\(0\\) and \\(1\\) are not. Hence, we get the factorization \\(f(x)=(x-2)(x^{2}+2x+2)=(x-2)g(x)\\). Clearly, \\(0\\) and \\(1\\) are not roots of \\(g(x)\\) since they are not roots of \\(f(x)\\); another calculation shows that \\(2\\) is not a root of \\(g(x)\\). Hence, \\(g(x)\\) is irreducible, and the above factorization is the desired one."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.26": {
        "Problem": "_Factor \\(x^{4}+x^{3}+x+3\\) completely in \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{5}[x]\\).\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.27": {
        "Problem": "1. _How many different monic irreducible polynomials of degree_ \\(2\\) _are there over the field_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{5}\\)_?\\_\n2. _How many different monic irreducible polynomials of degree_ \\(3\\) _are there over the field_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{5}\\)_?\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.28": {
        "Problem": "_Is \\(x^{4}+1\\) irreducible over the field of real numbers? The field of rational numbers? A field with \\(16\\) elements?_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.29": {
        "Problem": "_Decompose \\(x^{4}-4\\) and \\(x^{3}-2\\) into irreducibles over \\(\\mathbb{R}\\), over \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\), and over \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{3}\\) (the integers modulo \\(3\\)).\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.11.30": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(a\\) be an element in a field \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) and let \\(p\\) be a prime. Assume \\(a\\) is not a \\(p^{th}\\) power. Show that the polynomial \\(x^{p}-a\\) is irreducible in \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\)._",
        "Solution": "Suppose, to the contrary, that \\(x^{p}-a\\) has nontrivial factors \\(f(x)\\) and \\(g(x)\\) in \\(\\mathbb{F}[x]\\). Let \\(\\mathbb{K}\\) be a splitting field of \\(x^{p}-a\\). Then, in \\(\\mathbb{K}\\), there are elements \\(a*{1},\\ldots,a*{p}\\) such that \\(x^{p}-a=(x-a*{1})\\cdots(x-a*{p})\\). We may assume without loss of generality that \\(f(x)=(x-a*{1})\\cdots(x-a*{k})\\) and \\(g(x)=(x-a*{k+1})\\cdots(x-a*{p})\\). Therefore, \\(A=a*{1}\\cdots a*{k}=\\pm f(0)\\) and \\(B=a*{k+1}\\cdots a*{p}=\\pm g(0)\\) are both elements of \\(\\mathbb{F}\\). Further, since the \\(a*{j}\\)'s are zeros of \\(x^{p}-a\\), \\(a*{j}^{p}=a\\) for all \\(j\\). Hence, \\(A^{p}=a^{k}\\) and \\(B^{p}=a^{p-k}\\). Since \\(k\\) and \\(p\\) are relatively prime, there exist integers \\(x\\) and \\(y\\) such that \\(kx+py=1\\). Let \\(r=-y\\) and \\(s=x+y\\). Then \\(A^{s}/B^{r}\\) is an element of \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) and\n\n\\[\\left(\\frac{A^{s}}{B^{r}}\\right)^{p}=\\frac{a^{s}k}{a^{rp-rk}}=a^{kx+py}=a.\\]\n\nHence, \\(a\\) is a \\(p^{th}\\) power, contradicting our assumptions. Therefore, \\(x^{p}-a\\) must be irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{F}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.31": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(p\\) be a prime integer, \\(p\\equiv 3\\pmod{4}\\), and let \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}=\\mathbb{Z}/p\\mathbb{Z}\\). If \\(x^{4}+1\\) factors into a product \\(g(x)h(x)\\) of two quadratic polynomials in \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}[x]\\), prove that \\(g(x)\\) and \\(h(x)\\) are both irreducible over \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "Suppose \\(g(x)\\) (or \\(h(x)\\)) is not irreducible. Then \\(x^{4}+1\\) has a linear factor and, hence, a zero. In other words, there is an element \\(a\\in\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\) with \\(a^{4}=-1\\). It follows that \\(a^{8}=1\\), and since \\(a^{4}\\neq 1\\) (\\(p\\) is odd), \\(a\\) has order 8 in the multiplicative group \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}^{\\star}\\) of the field with \\(p\\) elements. But \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{p}^{\\star}\\) is a group of order \\(p-1\\equiv 2\\pmod{4}\\), so 8 cannot divide \\(p-1\\), and we have a contradiction."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.32": {
        "Problem": "_Let n be a positive integer and let \\(f\\) be a polynomial in \\(\\mathbb{R}[x]\\) of degree \\(n\\). Prove that there are real numbers \\(a_{0},a*{1},\\ldots,a*{n}\\), not all equal to zero, such that the polynomial\\_\n\n\\[\\sum*{i=0}^{n}a*{i}x^{2^{i}}\\]\n\n_is divisible by f._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(\\deg f=n\\). Then the collection of all real polynomials of \\(\\deg\\leq n-1\\) is an \\(m\\)-dimensional vector space. Hence, any collection of \\(n+1\\) polynomials of degree \\(\\leq n-1\\) is linearly dependent. By the Euclidean Algorithm [Her75, pag. 155], we have\n\n\\[x^{2^{0}} = q*{0}(x)f(x)+r*{0}(x)\\quad\\text{with }\\deg r*{0}<n\\] \\[x^{2^{1}} = q*{1}(x)f(x)+r*{1}(x)\\quad\\text{with }\\deg r*{1}<n\\] \\[\\vdots\\] \\[x^{2^{n}} = q*{n}(x)f(x)+r*{n}(x)\\quad\\text{with }\\deg r\\_{n}<n.\\]\n\nThe polynomials \\(r*{0},\\ldots,r*{n}\\) are linearly dependent, so, for some \\(\\alpha\\_{i}\\in\\mathbb{R}\\), we have\n\n\\[\\sum\\alpha*{i}r*{i}(x)=0.\\]\n\nTherefore,\n\n\\[p(x)=\\sum\\alpha*{i}x^{2^{i}}=f(x)\\sum\\alpha*{i}q\\_{i}(x)\\]\n\nand \\(f(x)|p(x)\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.11.33": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a field, \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\) the polynomial ring in one variable over \\(\\mathbf{F}\\), and \\(R\\) a subring of \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\) with \\(\\mathbf{F}\\subset R\\). Prove that there exists a finite set \\(\\{f_{1},f*{2},\\ldots,f*{n}\\}\\) of elements of \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\) such that \\(R=\\mathbf{F}[f_{1},f_{2},\\ldots,f_{n}]\\).\\_",
        "Solution": "Fix \\(f\\in R\\setminus\\mathbf{F}\\) of least degree \\(n\\), say. Choose polynomials \\(f*{1},f*{2},\\ldots,f*{n-1}\\) in \\(R\\) such that \\(\\deg f*{j}\\equiv j\\pmod{n}\\) and such that each \\(f*{j}\\) is of least degree with this property, \\(1\\leq j\\leq n-1\\), if such a polynomial exists, otherwise take \\(f*{j}=0\\). Let \\(f*{n}=f\\). We will prove that \\(R=\\mathbf{F}[f*{1},f*{2},\\ldots,f*{n}]\\). Suppose not, and fix \\(g\\in R\\setminus\\mathbf{F}[f_{1},f_{2},\\ldots,f_{n}]\\) of least degree, and suppose \\(\\deg g\\equiv j\\pmod{n}\\). For some \\(k\\geq 0\\), \\(\\deg g=\\deg(f*{n}^{k}f*{j})\\). Hence, \\(g-\\alpha f*{n}^{k}f*{j}\\) is of lower degree than \\(g\\) for some \\(\\alpha\\in\\mathbf{F}\\), and, by the minimality of \\(g\\), must lie in \\(\\mathbf{F}[f_{1},f_{2},\\ldots,f_{n}]\\). However, this implies that \\(g\\in\\mathbf{F}[f_{1},f_{2},\\ldots,f_{n}]\\) as well.\n\n### 6.12 Fields and Their Extensions"
    },
    "Problem 6.11.34": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a finite field with \\(q\\) elements and let \\(x\\) be an indeterminate. For \\(f\\) a polynomial in \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\), let \\(\\varphi_{f}\\) denote the corresponding function of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) into \\(\\mathbf{F}\\), defined by \\(\\varphi*{f}(a)=f(a)\\), \\((a\\in\\mathbf{F})\\). Prove that if \\(\\varphi\\) is any function of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) into \\(\\mathbf{F}\\), then there is an \\(f\\) in \\(\\mathbf{F}[x]\\) such that \\(\\varphi=\\varphi*{f}\\). Prove that \\(f\\) is uniquely determined by \\(\\varphi\\) to within addition of a multiple of \\(x^{q}-x\\).\\_\n\n### 6.12 Fields and Their Extensions",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.12.2": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that every finite integral domain is a field._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(R\\) be a finite integral domain. Let \\(0\\neq b\\in R\\) and enumerate the elements of \\(R\\) by \\(c*{1},c*{2}\\ldots,c*{n}\\). Since \\(R\\), has no zero divisors, cancellation shows that the elements \\(bc*{i}\\) are distinct. Since there are \\(n\\) of them, it follows that there is an element \\(c*{i*{0}}\\) such that \\(bc*{i*{0}}=1\\). Hence, \\(c*{i*{0}}\\) is the inverse of \\(b\\) and we are done."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.6": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\({\\bf F}=\\{a+b\\sqrt[3]{2}+c\\sqrt[3]{4}\\mid a,b,c\\in{\\mathbb{Q}}\\,\\}\\). Prove that \\({\\bf F}\\) is a field and each element in \\({\\bf F}\\) has a unique representation as \\(a+b\\sqrt[3]{2}+c\\sqrt[3]{4}\\) with \\(a,b,c\\in{\\mathbb{Q}}\\,\\). Find \\(\\left(1-\\sqrt[3]{2}\\right)^{-1}\\) in \\({\\bf F}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Since \\(x^{3}-2\\) is irreducible over \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\), \\(\\langle x^{3}-2\\rangle\\) is a maximal ideal in \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\), so \\(\\mathbb{F}=\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]/\\langle x^{3}-2\\rangle\\) is a field. Using the relationship \\(\\bar{x}^{3}=2\\), we get that every element of \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) can be written in the form \\(a+b\\bar{x}+c\\bar{x}^{2}\\), where \\(a,b,c\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\). Further, such a representation is unique, since otherwise we could find \\(a,b,c\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\), not all \\(0\\), with \\(a+b\\bar{x}+c\\bar{x}^{2}=0\\). On pulling back to \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\), we find that \\(x^{3}-2\\) divides \\(a+bx+cx^{2}\\), a contradiction.\n\nConsider the map \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{F}\\to\\mathbb{F}\\) given by \\(\\varphi(a)=a\\) if \\(a\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\), and \\(\\varphi(\\sqrt[3]{2}\\,)=\\bar{x}\\). Since \\((\\sqrt[3]{2}\\,)^{3}=2\\) and \\(\\bar{x}^{3}=2\\) this extends to a ring epimorphism in the obvious way. It is also one-to-one, since if \\(\\varphi(a+b\\sqrt[3]{2}+c\\sqrt[3]{4}\\,)=0\\) then \\(a+b\\bar{x}+c\\bar{x}^{2}=0\\), so \\(a=b=c=0\\). Hence, \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is the isomorphic image of a field, and it is field.\n\nFurther, by the isomorphism we see that every element can be expressed uniquely in the desired form. In particular, \\((1-\\sqrt[3]{2}\\,)(-1-\\sqrt[3]{2}-\\sqrt[3]{4}\\,)=1\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.7": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\({\\bf F}\\) be a finite field. Give a complete proof of the fact that the number of elements of \\({\\bf F}\\) is of the form \\(p^{r}\\), where \\(p\\geq 2\\) is a prime number and \\(r\\) is an integer \\(\\geq 1\\)._",
        "Solution": "Consider the ring homomorphism \\(\\varphi:\\mathbb{Z}\\to\\mathbb{F}\\) that satisfies \\(\\varphi(1)=1\\). Since \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is finite, \\(\\ker\\varphi\\neq 0\\). Since \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is a field, it has characteristic \\(p\\), where \\(p\\) is a prime number. Hence, \\(\\ker\\varphi\\) contains the ideal \\(\\langle p\\rangle\\), which is maximal. Therefore, \\(\\ker\\varphi=\\langle p\\rangle\\), and the image of \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\) is a subfield of \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\). Identify \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\) with this subfield. Then \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is a vector space over \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{p}\\), and it must be of finite dimension since \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) is finite. Let \\(\\dim\\mathbb{F}=r\\). A counting argument shows that \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) has \\(p^{r}\\) elements."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.8": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\({\\bf F}\\) be a field of characteristic \\(p>0\\), \\(p\\neq 3\\). If \\(\\alpha\\) is a zero of the polynomial \\(f(x)=x^{p}-x+3\\) in an extension field of \\({\\bf F}\\), show that \\(f(x)\\) has \\(p\\) distinct zeros in the field \\({\\bf F}(\\alpha)\\)._",
        "Solution": "Since \\(\\mathbb{F}\\) has characteristic \\(p\\), it contains a subfield isomorphic to \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\), which we identify with \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{p}\\). For \\(j\\in\\mathbb{Z}\\_{p}\\), \\(\\alpha+j\\) is an element of \\(\\mathbb{F}(\\alpha)\\). Using the identity \\((\\alpha+j)^{p}=\\alpha^{p}+j^{p}\\), we get\n\n\\[f(\\alpha+j)=\\alpha^{p}-\\alpha+3+j^{p}-j=0.\\]\n\nTherefore, \\(f\\) has \\(p\\) roots in \\(\\mathbb{F}(\\alpha)\\), which are clearly distinct."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.9": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(f(x)=x^{5}-8x^{3}+9x-3\\) and \\(g(x)=x^{4}-5x^{2}-6x+3\\). Prove that there is an integer \\(d\\) such that the polynomials \\(f(x)\\) and \\(g(x)\\) have a common root in the field \\({\\mathbb{Q}}\\left(\\sqrt{d}\\,\\right)\\). What is d?_",
        "Solution": "Notice that \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left[x\\right]\\) is an Euclidean domain, so the ideal \\(\\langle f,g\\rangle\\) is generated by a single polynomial, \\(h\\) say. \\(f\\) and \\(g\\) have a common root if and only if that root is also a root of \\(h\\). We can use the Euclidean algorithm to find \\(h=x^{2}+3x+1\\), which has roots \\(-3/2\\pm\\sqrt{5}/2\\). Therefore, \\(f\\) and \\(g\\) have exactly two common roots, both in \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\left(\\sqrt{5}\\,\\right)\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.10": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\({\\bf F}\\) be a field containing \\({\\mathbb{Q}}\\,\\) such that \\(\\left[{\\bf F}:{\\mathbb{Q}}\\,\\right]=2\\). Prove that there exists a unique integer \\(m\\) such that \\(m\\) has no multiple prime factors and \\({\\bf F}\\) is isomorphic to \\({\\mathbb{Q}}\\left(\\sqrt{m}\\,\\right)\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(x\\) be an element of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) that is not in \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\). Then \\(x\\) satisfies an equation \\(ax^{2}+bx+c=0\\) with \\(a\\), \\(b\\), and \\(c\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\). Completing the square, we see that \\(\\left(x+\\frac{a}{2}\\right)^{2}\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\), whereas \\(\\left(x+\\frac{a}{2}\\right)\\not\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\). Let \\(\\xi=\\left(x+\\frac{a}{2}\\right)\\). As \\(\\xi^{2}\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\), we can write it as \\(\\frac{c^{2}}{d^{2}}m\\), where \\(c,d,m\\in\\mathbb{Z}\\) and \\(m\\) is square free (i.e., \\(m\\) has no multiple prime factors). As \\(\\mathbf{F}=\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\left(\\xi\\right)=\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\left(\\frac{d}{c}\\xi\\right)\\), we get an isomorphism \\(\\mathbf{F}\\to\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\left(\\sqrt{m}\\right)\\) by sending \\(r+s\\left(\\frac{d}{c}\\xi\\right)\\) to \\(r+s\\sqrt{m}\\). The uniqueness of \\(m\\) follows from the fact that the elements of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) that are not in \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\) but whose squares are in \\(\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\) are those of the form \\(k\\xi\\) for some nonzero \\(k\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.11": {
        "Problem": "_Exhibit infinitely many pairwise nonisomorphic quadratic extensions of \\({\\mathbb{Q}}\\,\\) and show they are pairwise nonisomorphic._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(p*{1}=2\\), \\(p*{2}=3\\),..., be the prime numbers and \\(\\mathbf{F}_{i}=\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\left(\\sqrt{p_{i}}\\,\\right)\\). Claim: The fields \\(\\mathbf{F}_{i}\\) are pairwise nonisomorphic. Indeed, if \\(\\mathbf{F}_{i}\\) were isomorphic to \\(\\mathbf{F}_{j}\\), then there would exist \\(r\\in\\mathbf{K}_{j}\\) such that \\(r^{2}=p\\_{i}\\). Write such an \\(r\\) in the form\n\n\\[r=a+b\\sqrt{p\\_{j}}\\qquad a,b\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,.\\]\n\nThen\n\n\\[r^{2}=a^{2}+b^{2}p*{j}+2ab\\sqrt{p*{j}}=p\\_{i}\\]\n\nif and only if \\(ab=0\\). Therefore, either \\(p*{i}=c^{2}\\) or \\(p*{j}=c^{2}\\) for some \\(c\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\,\\), which contradicts the primality of \\(p*{i}\\) and \\(p*{j}\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\({\\mathbb{Q}}\\) be the field of rational numbers. For \\(\\theta\\) a real number, let \\({\\bf F}_{\\theta}={\\mathbb{Q}}(\\sin\\theta)\\) and \\({\\bf E}_{\\theta}={\\mathbb{Q}}\\left(\\sin\\frac{\\theta}{3}\\right)\\). Show that \\({\\bf E}_{\\theta}\\) is an extension field of \\({\\bf F}_{\\theta}\\), and determine all possibilities for \\(\\dim_{{\\bf F}_{\\theta}}{\\bf E}_{\\theta}\\)._",
        "Solution": "\\[\\left(\\cos\\frac{\\theta}{3}+i\\sin\\frac{\\theta}{3}\\right)^{3} = \\cos\\theta+i\\sin\\theta\\] \\[\\Rightarrow 3\\sin\\frac{\\theta}{3}-4\\sin^{3}\\frac{\\theta}{3}=\\sin\\theta\\] \\[\\Rightarrow E*{\\theta}\\supset F*{\\theta}\\]\n\nAll the possibilities can occur. For example\n\n\\[\\dim*{F*{\\theta}}E*{\\theta} = 1\\quad\\text{if}\\quad\\theta=\\frac{\\pi}{2}\\] \\[\\dim*{F*{\\theta}}E*{\\theta} = 2\\quad\\text{if}\\quad\\theta=\\pi\\] \\[\\dim*{F*{\\theta}}E\\_{\\theta} = 3\\quad\\text{if}\\quad\\theta=\\frac{\\pi}{6}\\]\n\nIn the last example, \\(4x^{3}-3x+1/2\\) or \\(8x^{3}-6x+1\\) is irreducible because \\(\\pm 1\\), \\(\\pm 1/2\\), \\(\\pm 1/4\\), and \\(\\pm 1/8\\) are not roots of the above polynomial."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.13": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a finite field of cardinality \\(p^{n}\\), with \\(p\\) prime and \\(n>0\\), and let \\(G\\) be the group of invertible 2\\(\\times\\)2 matrices with coefficients in \\(\\mathbf{F}\\)._\n\n1. _Prove that_ \\(G\\) _has order_ \\((p^{2n}-1)(p^{2n}-p^{n})\\)_._\n2. _Show that any p-Sylow subgroup of_ \\(G\\) _is isomorphic to the additive group of_ \\(\\mathbf{F}\\)_._",
        "Solution": "1. A \\(2\\times 2\\) matrix over \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) is invertible if and only if the first column is nonzero and the second is not a \\(\\mathbf{F}\\)-multiple of the first.\n\nThis gives \\(|{\\bf F}|^{2}-1=p^{2n}-1\\) possibilities for the first column of an invertible matrix, and, given the first column, \\(|{\\bf F}|^{2}-|{\\bf F}|=p^{2n}-p^{n}\\) for the second, hence the result. See also Problem 7.1.1 for a more general solution.\n\n2. The map \\({\\bf F}\\to G\\) sending \\(a\\) to \\(\\left(\\begin{smallmatrix}1&a\\\\ 0&1\\end{smallmatrix}\\right)\\) is easily checked to be an injective group homomorphism. Its image is a subgroup \\(S\\) of \\(G\\) that is isomorphic to the additive group of \\({\\bf F}\\) and that, consequently, has order \\(p^{n}\\). By 1., this is the largest power of \\(p\\) dividing the order of \\(G\\). Hence, \\(S\\) is, in fact, a \\(p\\)-Sylow subgroup of \\(G\\). Since all \\(p\\)-Sylow subgroups of a finite group are conjugate (and hence isomorphic), this implies the result."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.14": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(p\\) be an odd prime and \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}\\) the field of \\(p\\) elements. How many elements of \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}\\) have square roots in \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}\\)? How many have cube roots in \\(\\mathbf{F}_{p}\\)?_",
        "Solution": "The zero element of \\({\\bf F}_{p}\\) obviously has a unique square root and a unique cube root. Let \\({\\bf F}_{p}^{_}\\) denote the multiplicative group of nonzero elements of \\({\\bf F}*{p}\\). It is a cyclic group of order \\(p-1\\). Since \\(p-1\\) is even, the homomorphism \\(x\\to x^{2}\\) of \\({\\bf F}*{p}^{_}\\) into itself has a kernel of order 2, which means that its range has order \\((p-1)/2\\). There are, thus, \\(1+(p-1)/2\\) elements of \\({\\bf F}\\_{p}\\) with square roots.\n\nIf \\(p-1\\) is not divisible by 3, the homomorphism \\(x\\to x^{3}\\) of \\({\\bf F}_{p}^{\\*}\\) into itself has a trivial kernel, and so every element of \\({\\bf F}_{p}\\) has a cube root. If 3 divides \\(p-1\\), then the preceding homomorphism has a kernel of order 3, so its range has order \\((p-1)/3\\). In this case, there are \\(1+(p-1)/3\\) elements of \\({\\bf F}\\_{p}\\) with cube roots."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.15": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a finite field with \\(q\\) elements. Say that a function \\(f:\\mathbf{F}\\rightarrow\\mathbf{F}\\) is a polynomial function if there are elements \\(a_{0},a*{1},\\ldots,a*{n}\\) of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) such that \\(f(x)=a*{0}+a*{1}x+\\cdots+a*{n}x^{n}\\) for all \\(x\\in\\mathbf{F}\\). How many polynomial functions are there?*",
        "Solution": "All functions are polynomials. A polynomial with the value 1 at 0 and 0 elsewhere is \\(p(x)=1-x^{q-1}\\); from this one, we can construct any function by considering sums \\(\\sum f*{i}\\cdot p(x-x*{i})\\). Thus, there are \\(q^{q}\\) such functions, and that many polynomials. Another way is to observe that all polynomials of degree, at most, \\(q-1\\) define nonzero functions unless the polynomial is the zero polynomial."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.16": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) be a finite field, and suppose that the subfield of \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) generated by \\(\\{x^{3}\\mid x\\in\\mathbf{F}\\}\\) is different from \\(\\mathbf{F}\\). Show that \\(\\mathbf{F}\\) has cardinality \\(4\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\({\\bf K}\\) be that subfield. The homomorphism of multiplicative groups \\({\\bf F}^{_}\\to{\\bf K}^{_}\\) sending \\(x\\) to \\(x^{3}\\) has a kernel of order, at most, 3, so \\(|{\\bf K}^{_}|\\geq|{\\bf F}^{_}|/3\\), that is, \\((|{\\bf F}|-1)/(|{\\bf K}|-1)\\leq 3\\). Also, if the extension degree \\([{\\bf F}:{\\bf K}]\\) equals \\(n\\), then \\(n\\geq 2\\), so \\(|{\\bf F}|=|{\\bf K}|^{n}\\geq|{\\bf K}|^{2}\\), and \\((|{\\bf F}|-1)/(|{\\bf K}|-1)\\geq|{\\bf K}|+1\\), with equality if and only if \\(n=2\\). Thus, \\(3\\geq|{\\bf K}|+1\\), which gives \\(|{\\bf K}|=2\\), \\(n=2\\), and \\(|{\\bf F}|=2^{2}=4\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.12.17": {
        "Problem": "_Suppose that \\(A\\) is a commutative algebra with identity over \\(\\mathbb{C}\\) (i.e., \\(A\\) is a commutative ring containing \\(\\mathbb{C}\\) as a subring with identity). Suppose further that \\(a^{2}\\neq 0\\) for all nonzero elements \\(a\\in A\\). Show that if the dimension of \\(A\\) as a vector space over \\(\\mathbb{C}\\) is finite and at least two, then the equations \\(a^{2}=a\\) is satisfied by at least three distinct elements \\(a\\in A\\)._\n\n### Elementary Number Theory",
        "Solution": "As \\(A\\) has dimension at least 2 as a vector space over \\({\\mathbb{C}}\\), it contains an element \\(a\\) which is not in the subspace spanned by the identity element \\(1\\in A\\). Since \\(A\\) has finite dimension over \\({\\mathbb{C}}\\), there exists a complex number \\(\\lambda\\) such that \\((a-\\lambda 1)x=0\\) for some nonzero \\(x\\in A\\). Let \\({\\mathfrak{C}}\\) be the ideal generated by \\(b=a-\\lambda 1\\), and \\(\\mathfrak{F}=\\{x\\in A\\,|\\,bx=0\\}\\) the annihilator of \\(b\\). We have \\({\\mathfrak{C}}\\cap\\mathfrak{F}=\\{0\\}\\) since all the elements of \\({\\mathfrak{C}}\\cap\\mathfrak{F}\\) have zero square. As the dimensions of \\({\\mathfrak{C}}\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{F}\\) add up to the dimension of \\(A\\) we must have \\(A={\\mathfrak{C}}\\oplus\\mathfrak{F}\\) as vector spaces over \\({\\mathbb{C}}\\). Since \\({\\mathfrak{C}}\\) and \\(\\mathfrak{F}\\) are ideals in \\(A\\), \\(A={\\mathfrak{C}}\\oplus\\mathfrak{F}\\) as rings. Let \\(1=e+f\\) with \\(e\\in{\\mathfrak{C}}\\) and \\(f\\in\\mathfrak{F}\\). Then \\(e^{2}=e\\), \\(f^{2}=f\\) and neither of them is zero or 1.\n\n### 6.13 Elementary Number Theory"
    },
    "Problem 6.13.1": {
        "Problem": "_Prove that if six people are riding together in an Evans Hall elevator, there is either a three-person subset of mutual friends (each knows the other two) or a three-person subset of mutual strangers (each knows neither of the other two)._",
        "Solution": "Let the six people be Aline, Laura, Lucia, Manuel, Raquel, and Stephanie. Fix one of them, Manuel, say. The five girls form two sets: \\(X\\) (Manuel's friends) and \\(Y\\) (the others). By the Pigeonhole Principle [11, pag. 127], one of these sets has cardinality at least 3. Suppose it is \\(X\\) that contains at least three elements, say \\(\\{\\)Aline, Laura, Stephanie\\(\\}\\subset X\\). If Aline, Laura, and Stephanie are pairwise strangers, we are done. Otherwise, two of them are friends of each other, Stephanie and Aline, say. Then Manuel, Aline, and Stephanie are mutual friends. If the set with three or more elements is \\(Y\\), a similar argument leads to the same conclusion."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.2": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(m\\geq 0\\) be an integer. Let \\(a_{1},a*{2},\\ldots,a*{m}\\) be integers and let\\_\n\n\\[f(x)=\\sum*{i=1}^{m}\\frac{a*{i}x^{i}}{i!}\\]\n\n_Show that if \\(d\\geq 0\\) is an integer then \\(f(x)^{d}/d!\\) can be expressed in the form_\n\n\\[\\sum*{i=0}^{md}\\frac{b*{i}x\\_{i}}{i!}\\]\n\n_where the \\(b_{i}\\) are integers.\\_",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.13.3": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(p\\) be an odd prime. Let \\(Q(p)\\) be the set of integers \\(a\\), \\(0\\leq a\\leq p-1\\), for which the congruence_\n\n\\[x^{2}\\equiv a\\pmod{p}\\]\n\n_has a solution. Show that \\(Q(p)\\) has cardinality \\((p+1)/2\\)._",
        "Solution": "If \\(a=0\\), the congruence has the trivial solution \\(x=0\\). For \\(1\\leq a\\leq p-1\\), if \\(x^{2}\\equiv a\\pmod{p}\\), we have\n\n\\[(p-x)^{2}=p^{2}-2xp+x^{2}\\equiv a\\pmod{p}\\]\n\nso, for \\(a\\neq 0\\), there are two solutions of the quadratic congruence in each complete set of residues mod p. We conclude, then, that the total number is \\(1+(p-1)/2=(p+1)/2\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.4": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(p\\) be an odd prime. If the congruence \\(x^{2}\\equiv-1\\pmod{p}\\) has a solution, show that \\(p\\equiv 1\\pmod{4}\\)._",
        "Solution": "By Fermat's Little Theorem [10, pag. 80], [11, pag. 44], we have, raising both sides of the congruence \\(-1\\equiv x^{2}\\pmod{p}\\) to the power \\((p-1)/2\\),\n\n\\[(-1)^{\\frac{p-1}{2}}\\equiv x^{p-1}\\equiv 1\\pmod{p}\\]\n\nwhich implies that \\((p-1)/2\\) is even, and the result follows."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.5": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(n\\geq 2\\) be an integer such that \\(2^{n}+n^{2}\\) is prime. Prove that_\n\n\\[n\\equiv 3\\pmod{6}.\\]",
        "Solution": "Let \\(f(n)=2^{n}+n^{2}\\). If \\(f(n)\\) is prime, then it is congruent with 1, or 5 \\(\\pmod{6}\\). Suppose \\(f(n)=6k+1\\) for some integer \\(k\\). We have\n\n\\[2^{f(n)}+f(n)^{2}=2^{6k+1}+36k^{2}+12k+1=\\left(2^{2}\\right)^{3k}2+36k^{2}+12k+1\\]\n\nwhich is a multiple of 3. If \\(f(n)=6k+5\\), we have\n\n\\[2^{f(n)}+f(n)^{2}=\\left(2^{2}\\right)^{3k}2^{2}2+36k^{2}+60k+25\\equiv 2+1\\equiv 0 \\pmod{3}\\]\n\nso \\(f(n)\\) is a composite as well."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.6": {
        "Problem": "_1. Show that the set of all units in a ring form a group under multiplication. (A unit is an element having a multiplicative inverse.)_ 2. _In the ring_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\) \\_of integers_ \\(\\bmod n\\)_, show that_ \\(k\\) _is a unit if and only if_ \\(k\\) _and_ \\(n\\) _are relatively prime._ 3. _Suppose_ \\(n=pq\\)_, where_ \\(p\\) _and_ \\(q\\) _are primes. Prove that the number of units in_ \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{n}\\) \\_is_ \\((p-1)(q-1)\\)_._",
        "Solution": "1. It is enough to show that the set of units is closed for multiplication. Let \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) be units with \\(a\\alpha\\equiv 1\\pmod{n}\\), \\(b\\beta\\equiv 1\\pmod{n}\\). Then, clearly, \\(\\alpha\\) and \\(\\beta\\) are also units, and we have\n\n\\[(ab)(\\beta\\alpha)\\equiv 1\\pmod{n}\\]\n\nso \\(ab\\) is also a unit.\n\n2. The congruence \\(ka\\equiv 1\\pmod{n}\\) is equivalent to the equation \\(ka=mn+1\\) for some integer \\(m\\). As all integer linear combinations of \\(k\\) and \\(n\\) are multiples of \\(\\gcd\\{k,n\\}\\), the first congruence has a solution iff \\(\\gcd\\{k,n\\}=1\\).\n\n3. Let \\(\\varphi\\) be Euler's totient function [Sta89, pag. 77], [Hcr75, pag. 43]. As \\(\\varphi\\) is multiplicative, we have\n\n\\[\\varphi(n)=\\varphi(p)\\varphi(q)=(p-1)(q-1).\\]"
    },
    "Problem 6.13.7": {
        "Problem": "_Which rational numbers \\(t\\) are such that_\n\n\\[3t^{3}+10t^{2}-3t\\]\n\n_is an integer?_",
        "Solution": "Let \\(p(t)=3t^{3}+10t^{2}-3t\\) and \\(n/m\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\) ; \\(\\gcd\\{n,m\\}=1\\). We can assume \\(m\\neq\\pm 1\\). If \\(p(n/m)=k\\in\\mathbb{Q}\\), then \\(m|3\\) and \\(n|k\\). Therefore, we have \\(m=\\pm 3\\).\n\nSuppose \\(m=3\\). We have\n\n\\[p\\left(\\frac{n}{3}\\right)=n\\left(\\frac{n^{2}}{9}+10\\frac{n}{9}-1\\right).\\]\n\nThis expression represents an integer exactly when \\(n^{2}+10n=n(n+10)\\equiv 0\\pmod{9}\\). As \\(\\gcd\\{n,3\\}=1\\), this means \\(n+10\\equiv 0\\pmod{9}\\), that is, \\(n\\equiv 8\\pmod{9}\\).\n\nA similar argument for the case \\(m=-3\\) shows that the numbers \\(n/(-3)\\) with \\(n\\equiv 1\\pmod{9}\\) produce integer values in \\(p\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.8": {
        "Problem": "_Show the denominator of \\(\\left(\\begin{array}{c}1/2\\\\ n\\end{array}\\right)\\) is a power of \\(2\\) for all integers \\(n\\)._",
        "Solution": "\\[\\binom{1/2}{n} =\\frac{(\\frac{1}{2})(\\frac{1}{2}-1)\\cdots(\\frac{1}{2}-(n-1))}{n!} =\\frac{(-1)^{n-1}\\cdot 3\\cdot 5\\cdots(2n-1)}{2^{n}n!}\\] \\[=\\frac{(-1)^{n-1}\\cdot 2\\cdot 3\\cdot 4\\cdot 5\\cdots 2n}{(2^{n}n!)^{ 2}}=\\frac{(-1)^{n-1}}{2^{2n}}\\cdot\\binom{2n}{n}\\]"
    },
    "Problem 6.13.9": {
        "Problem": "_Let n be a positive integer._\n\n1. _Show that the binomial coefficient_ \\[c*{n}=\\left(\\begin{array}{c}2n\\\\ n\\end{array}\\right)\\] \\_is even.*\n2. _Prove that_ \\(c*{n}\\) \\_is divisible by* \\(4\\) _if and only if n is not a power of_ \\(2\\)_._",
        "Solution": "A counting argument shows that the power of 2 which divides \\(n!\\) is given by\n\n\\[\\sum\\_{k\\geq 1}\\left\\lfloor\\frac{n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor,\\]\n\nwhere \\(\\lfloor x\\rfloor\\) denotes the largest integer less than or equal to \\(x\\). Since \\(c*{n}=(2n)!/(n!)^{2}\\), to show that \\(c*{n}\\) is even it suffices to show that\n\n\\[\\sum*{k\\geq 1}\\left\\lfloor\\frac{2n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor>2\\sum*{k\\geq 1}\\left\\lfloor \\frac{n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor.\\]\n\nSuppose \\(2^{r}\\leq n<2^{r+1}\\). For \\(k\\leq r\\), there is an \\(r*{k}\\), \\(0\\leq r*{k}<1\\), such that\n\n\\[\\frac{n}{2^{k}}=\\left\\lfloor\\frac{n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor+r*{k}\\]\\[\\frac{2n}{2^{k}}=2\\left\\lfloor\\frac{n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor+2r*{k}\\]\n\nso\n\n\\[\\left\\lfloor\\frac{2n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor\\geq 2\\left\\lfloor\\frac{n}{2^{k}}\\right\\rfloor\\]\n\nand equality holds if and only if \\(n\\) is a power of \\(2\\). For \\(k=r+1\\), we have that \\(\\left\\lfloor n/2^{r+1}\\right\\rfloor=0\\) while \\(\\left\\lfloor 2n/2^{r+1}\\right\\rfloor=1\\). Finally, for \\(k>r\\), the terms in both sums are \\(0\\). Hence, we see that the above inequality holds. Further, we see that the left side is \\(2\\) or more greater than the right side (i.e., \\(c\\_{n}\\) is divisible by \\(4\\)) if and only \\(n\\) is not a power of \\(2\\).\n\nSolution to 6.13.10:We may assume that \\(n>3\\). Converting the sum into a single fraction, we get\n\n\\[\\frac{n!/1+n!/2+\\cdots+n!/n}{n!}.\\]\n\nLet \\(r\\) be such that \\(2^{r}|n!\\) but \\(2^{r+1}\\) does not divide \\(n!\\), and \\(s\\) be such that \\(2^{s}\\) is the largest power of \\(2\\) less than or equal to \\(n\\). Since \\(n>3\\), \\(r>s>0\\). The only integer in \\(1,\\ldots,n\\), divisible by \\(2^{s}\\) is \\(2^{s}\\). Hence, for \\(1\\leq k\\leq n\\), \\(n!/k\\) is divisible by \\(2^{r-s}\\), and every term except \\(1\\) is divisible by \\(2^{r-s+1}\\). So\n\n\\[\\frac{n!/1+n!/2+\\cdots+n!/n}{n!}=\\frac{2^{r-s}(2j+1)}{2^{r}k}=\\frac{2j+1}{2^{s }k}\\]\n\nfor some integers \\(j\\) and \\(k\\). The numerator is odd and the denominator is even, so this fraction is never an integer.\n\nSolution to 6.13.11:Recall that if \\(p*{1},p*{2},\\ldots\\) is the sequence of prime numbers and \\(x=\\prod p*{i}^{\\xi*{i}}\\) and \\(y=\\prod p*{i}^{\\eta*{i}}\\), we have\n\n\\[\\gcd\\{x,y\\}=\\prod p*{i}^{\\min\\{\\xi*{i},\\eta*{i}\\}}\\qquad\\operatorname{lcm}\\{x,y\\}=\\prod p*{i}^{\\max\\{\\xi*{i},\\eta*{i}\\}}.\\]\n\nLet\n\n\\[a=\\prod p*{i}^{\\alpha*{i}}\\quad b=\\prod p*{i}^{\\beta*{i}}\\quad c=\\prod p*{i}^ {\\gamma*{i}}\\]\n\nwe have\n\n\\[\\gcd\\{a,\\operatorname{lcm}\\{b,c\\}\\} =\\prod p*{i}^{\\min\\{\\alpha*{i},\\max\\{\\beta*{i},\\gamma*{i}\\}\\}}\\] \\[=\\prod p*{i}^{\\max\\{\\min\\{\\alpha*{i},\\beta*{i}\\},\\min\\{\\alpha*{i },\\gamma\\_{i}\\}\\}}\\] \\[=\\operatorname{lcm}\\{\\gcd\\{a,b\\},\\gcd\\{a,c\\}.\\}\\]\n\nSolution to 6.13.12:There are nine prime numbers \\(\\leq 25\\):\n\n\\[p*{1}=2,\\quad p*{2}=3,\\quad p*{3}=5,\\quad p*{4}=7,\\quad p*{5}=11,\\]\\[p*{6}=13,\\quad p*{7}=17,\\quad p*{8}=19,\\quad p\\_{9}=23.\\]\n\nBy unique factorization, for each \\(1\\leq a\\leq 25\\) there is an integer sequence \\(v(a)=(v*{j}(a))*{j=1}^{9}\\) with \\(a=\\prod*{j=1}^{9}p*{j}^{v*{j}(a)}.\\) The 10 sequences \\(v(a*{i})\\in\\mathbb{Q}^{9}\\) must be linearly dependent, so\n\n\\[\\sum*{i=1}^{10}n*{i}v*{j}(a*{i})=0\\]\n\nfor all \\(j\\), for some rational numbers \\(n*{i}\\) which are not all 0. Multiplying by a common multiple of the denominators, we can assume that the \\(n*{i}\\)'s are integers. So\n\n\\[\\prod*{i=1}^{10}a*{i}^{n*{i}}=\\prod*{j=1}^{9}p*{j}^{\\sum*{i=1}^{10}n*{i}v*{j}(a \\_{i})}=1,\\]\n\nas required."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.10": {
        "Problem": "_Suppose that \\(n>1\\) is an integer. Prove that the sum_\n\n\\[1+\\frac{1}{2}+\\cdots+\\frac{1}{n}\\]\n\n_is not an integer._",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.13.12": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(a_{1},a*{2},\\ldots,a*{10}\\) be integers with \\(1\\leq a*{i}\\leq 25\\), for \\(1\\leq i\\leq 10\\). Prove that there exist integers \\(n*{1},n*{2},\\ldots,n*{10}\\), not all zero, such that\\_\n\n\\[\\prod*{i=1}^{10}a*{i}^{n\\_{i}}=1.\\]",
        "Solution": null
    },
    "Problem 6.13.13": {
        "Problem": "_The number \\(21982145917308330487013369\\) is the thirteenth power of a positive integer. Which positive integer?_",
        "Solution": "Denote the given number by \\(n\\) and let \\(n=a^{13}.\\) By counting digits, we see that \\(n<10^{26},\\) so \\(a<100.\\) As \\(8^{13}=7934527488,\\) we have \\(80^{13}<n\\) and \\(a>80.\\) Note that \\(n\\equiv 9\\pmod{10}.\\) The integers \\(c<10\\) such that \\(c^{k}\\equiv 9\\pmod{10}\\) for some \\(k\\) are 3, 7 and 9. But \\(3^{4}\\equiv 7^{4}\\equiv 9^{4}\\equiv 1\\pmod{10}\\) and \\(13=3\\cdot 4+1,\\) so \\(c^{13}\\equiv c^{3\\cdot 4}c\\equiv c\\equiv 9\\pmod{10}\\) so \\(c=9.\\) Hence, \\(a=89\\) or \\(a=99.\\) As 3 does not divide \\(n\\), 3 does not divide \\(a.\\) Hence, \\(a=89.\\)"
    },
    "Problem 6.13.14": {
        "Problem": "_Determine the rightmost decimal digit of_\n\n\\[A=17^{17^{17}}.\\]",
        "Solution": "Since \\(17\\equiv 7\\pmod{10},\\)\n\n\\[A\\equiv 7^{17^{17}}\\pmod{10}.\\]\n\nSince \\((7,10)=1,\\) we can apply Euler's Theorem [14, pag. 80], [10, pag. 43]:\n\n\\[7^{\\varphi(10)}\\equiv 1\\pmod{10}.\\]\n\nThe numbers \\(k\\) such that \\(1\\leq k\\leq 10\\) and \\((k,10)=1\\) are precisely 1, 3, 7, and 9, so \\(\\varphi(10)=4.\\) Now \\(17\\equiv 1\\pmod{4},\\) so \\(17^{17}\\equiv 1\\pmod{4}.\\) Thus,\n\n\\[7^{17^{17}}\\equiv 7^{1}\\equiv 7\\pmod{10}\\]\n\nand the rightmost decimal digit of \\(A\\) is 7."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.15": {
        "Problem": "_Determine the last digit of_\n\n\\[23^{23^{23^{23}}}\\]\n\n_in the decimal system._",
        "Solution": "As \\(23\\equiv 3\\pmod{10},\\) it suffices to find \\(3^{23^{23^{23}}}\\pmod{10}.\\) We have \\(\\varphi(10)=4,\\) where \\(\\varphi\\) is Euler's totient function, and, by Euler's Theorem [14, pag. 80], \\([10],3^{r}\\equiv 3^{s}\\pmod{10}\\) when \\(r\\equiv s\\pmod{4}.\\) So we will find \\(23^{23^{23}}\\pmod{4}.\\) We have \\(23\\equiv 3\\pmod{4},\\) so \\(23^{23^{23}}\\equiv 3^{23^{23}}\\pmod{4}.\\) As \\(-1\\equiv 3\\pmod{4},\\)\\(3^{23^{23}}\\equiv(-1)^{23^{23}}\\equiv-1\\pmod{4},\\) because \\(23^{23}\\) is odd. Hence, \\(23^{23^{23}}\\equiv 3\\pmod{4},\\) and \\(3^{23^{23^{23}}}\\equiv 3^{3}\\equiv 7\\pmod{10}.\\)"
    },
    "Problem 6.13.16": {
        "Problem": "_Show that you can represent the set of non-negative integers, \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{+}\\), as the union of two disjoint subsets \\(N*{1}\\) and \\(N*{2}\\)\\((N*{1}\\cap N*{2}=\\emptyset,\\ N*{1}\\cup N*{2}=\\mathbb{Z}_{+})\\) such that neither \\(N_{1}\\) nor \\(N*{2}\\) contains an infinite arithmetic progression.*",
        "Solution": "Let\n\n\\[\\begin{array}{rcl}N*{0}&=&\\{0,1\\}\\cup\\{4,5,6\\}\\cup\\{11,12,13,14,15\\}\\cup\\cdots \\\\ N*{1}&=&\\{2,3\\}\\cup\\{7,8,9,10\\}\\cup\\{16,17,18,19,20,21\\}\\cup\\cdots\\end{array}\\]\n\nWe have\n\n\\[N*{0}\\cap N*{1}=\\emptyset,\\qquad N*{0}\\cup N*{1}=\\mathbb{Z}\\_{+}\\]\n\nand, clearly, neither can contain an arithmetic progression."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.17": {
        "Problem": "_Let \\(\\varphi\\) be Euler's totient function; so if \\(n\\) is a positive integer, then \\(\\varphi(n)\\) is the number of integers \\(m\\) for which \\(1\\leq m\\leq n\\) and \\(\\gcd\\{n,m\\}=1\\). Let \\(a\\) and \\(k\\) be two integers, with \\(a>1\\), \\(k>0\\). Prove that \\(k\\) divides \\(\\varphi(a^{k}-1)\\)._",
        "Solution": "Consider the ring \\(\\mathbb{Z}_{a^{k}-1}\\). Since \\(a>1\\), \\((a,a^{k}-1)=1\\), so \\(a\\in\\mathbb{Z}_{a^{k}-1}^{_}\\). Further, it is clear that \\(k\\) is the least integer such that \\(a^{k}\\equiv 1\\pmod{a^{k}-1}\\), so \\(k\\) is the order of \\(a\\) in \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{a^{k}-1}^{_}\\). Hence, by Lagrange's Theorem [10, pag. 41], \\(k\\) divides the order of the group \\(\\mathbb{Z}\\_{a^{k}-1}^{\\*}\\), which is \\(\\varphi(a^{k}-1)\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.18": {
        "Problem": "_Determine the greatest common divisor of the elements of the set \\(\\{n^{13}-n\\mid n\\in\\mathbb{Z}\\}\\)._",
        "Solution": "Let \\(N\\) be the desired greatest common divisor. By Fermat's Little Theorem [11, pag. 80], [10, pag. 44], we have\n\n\\[n^{13}\\equiv(n^{6})^{2}n\\equiv(n^{3})^{2}n\\equiv n^{4}\\equiv n^{2}\\equiv n \\pmod{2}.\\]\n\nHence, \\(2|(n^{13}-n)\\) for all \\(n\\), so \\(2|N\\). An identical calculation shows that \\(p|N\\) for \\(p\\in\\{3,5,7,13\\}\\). Since these are all prime, their product, \\(2730\\), divides \\(N\\). However, \\(2^{13}-2=8190=3\\cdot 2730\\), so \\(N\\) is either \\(2730\\) or \\(3\\cdot 2730\\). As \\(3^{13}-3=3(3^{12}-1)\\) is not divisible by \\(9\\), \\(N=2730\\)."
    },
    "Problem 6.13.19": {
        "Problem": "_For \\(n\\) a positive integer, let \\(d(n)\\) denote the number of positive integers that divide \\(n\\). Prove that \\(d(n)\\) is odd if and only if n is a perfect square._\n\n## Chapter 7 Linear Algebra\n\n### 7.1 Vector Spaces",
        "Solution": "Let\n\n\\[n=p*{1}^{k*{1}}p*{2}^{k*{2}}\\cdots p*{n}^{k*{n}}\\]\n\nbe the factorization into a product of prime powers (\\(p*{1}<p*{2}<\\cdots<p\\_{n}\\)) for \\(n\\). The positive integer divisors of \\(n\\) are then the numbers\n\n\\[p*{1}^{j*{1}}p*{2}^{j*{2}}\\cdots p*{n}^{j*{n}}\\qquad 0\\leq j\\leq k\\_{j}.\\]\n\nIt follows that \\(d(n)\\) is the number of \\(r\\)-tuples \\((j*{1},j*{2},\\ldots,j\\_{r})\\) satisfying the preceding conditions. In other words,\n\n\\[d(n)=(k*{1}+1)(k*{2}+1)\\cdots(k\\_{n}+1),\\]\n\nwhich is odd iff each \\(k\\_{i}\\) is even; in other words, iff \\(n\\) is a perfect square.\n\n## Chapter 7 Linear Algebra\n\n### 7.1 Vector Spaces"
    }
}
